Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
We are gathered here today
to immortalize in song
the life and untimely death
of a great legend.
- Rango.
- So sit back, relax,
and enjoy your low-calorie popcorn
and assorted confections
while we tell you the strange
and bewildering tale of a hero
who has yet to enter his own story.
Crunchy, creamy, cookie,
candy, cupcake.
Okay, everybody,
let's take it from the top.
The stage is set,
the night moist with apprehension.
Alone in her chamber, the princess
prepares to take her own life.
"It is far better to nourish worms
than to live without love."
She reaches for the poisoned chalice.
Meanwhile, the wicked Malvolio
plots his ascension to the throne
while her aging father lies gravely ill.
"Yes, I am gravely ill."
"Hark, who goes there?"
'Tis I, the much-anticipated hero,
returning to rescue
his emotionally unstable maiden!
Unhand her, you jailers of virtue,
or taste the bitter sting
of my vengeance!
The sting of my...
Dr. Marx?
Dr. Marx,
I'm not getting anything from you.
People, we've talked about this.
Acting is reacting.
Victor, you were wooden!
There, I said it.
Mr. Timms? You were good.
Perhaps a little too good.
What's that, Victor? My character's
undefined? That's absurd.
I know who I am.
I'm the guy, the protagonist, the hero.
Every story needs a hero.
I mean, who else is better qualified
to bask in the adulation
of his numerous companions?
The stage is waiting.
The audience thirsts for adventure.
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
I could be the sea cap'n
returning from a mighty voyage
to reclaim his mechanical arm!
Or I could be the rogue anthropologist,
battling pythons down in the Congo!
Down, Chongo, down!
And if you desire romance,
I will become the greatest lover
the world has ever known!
I couldn't help but notice you
noticing me noticing you.
You know, the womens find me
uncomfortably good looking.
But you seem remarkably at ease.
Stop it. No, really.
Well, if you must. What are you doing?
That tickles. Are those real?
That's it! Conflict.
Victor, you were right.
I have been undefined.
People, I've had an epiphany.
The hero cannot exist in a vacuum!
What our story needs is an ironic,
unexpected event
that will propel the hero into conflict!
Mr. Timms?
That's right! You!
Don't be shy. Come on.
It's okay.
That's it, a little closer.
Good.
I won't bite you.
I need a little help here.
Are you okay?
I must get to the other side.
The other side? You mean, just now,
that was you crossing the road?
That's why the...
Why'd you do that?
This is my quest. He waits for me.
What? Who?
The Spirit of the West, amigo. The one.
They say he rides an alabaster carriage
with golden guardians to protect him.
What are you talking about?
Enlightenment.
We are nothing without it.
Nothing? Your delusional quest
just ruined my life!
I had an incredibly complex
social network going!
Highly sophisticated friends!
I was very popular!
Friends? I don't see no friends.
You are a very lonely lizard.
Look, I need water, hydration.
My teeth are chapped.
I need lotion.
I'm down to one layer of skin already.
Pretty soon,
I'm going to start seeing my insides.
Not unlike what you've got going there.
Listen, I can't survive
in the desert, okay?
I... I don't belong here.
That may be true, but here you are.
Now help me up
and I will help you find what you seek.
- You will?
- And perhaps more.
Quickly. I must get back to my quest.
- You mean you've done this before?
- Yes. Many times.
Come, come. That's it, pull my finger.
The Spirit is waiting for me.
Okay, okay.
Okay. That's not going to work.
I must get to the other side.
Why don't you just wait
until there are no cars coming?
It's not so easy as it looks.
What?
Is a metaphor.
There's another one!
I knew it.
You need a little help, amigo?
I think the metaphor broke my spleen.
The path to knowledge
is fraught with consequence.
I'm just looking for the path to water.
If you want to find water,
you must first find Dirt.
Dirt.
Destiny, she is kind to you.
Tomorrow is Wednesday.
The water comes.
At noon, the townspeople gather
for a mysterious ritual.
A town? You mean, with real people
and everything? Where?
A day's journey. Follow your shadow.
You want me to just walk out
into the desert?
That's the way.
Okay. So you're saying
there's a town, a real town,
not a metaphor town.
Go on. It's okay.
Okay.
Well, then, I'm going.
I am leaving the road now!
I'm walking into the desert!
Alone!
We all have our journeys to make!
I will see you on the other side.
Welcome, amigo
To the land without end
The desert and death
Are the closest of friends
We sing of his courage
In magnificent song
But pay close attention
He won't be here long
As the birds pluck his eyes
The sun bleaches his bones
See his entrails get scattered
Watch him lose his cojones
Here in the Mojave Desert,
animals have had millions of years
to adapt to the harsh environment.
But the lizard? He is going to die.
"Four score and seven years ago,
our fathers..."
- Don't move.
- What?
- Don't move!
- Not moving.
Not moving.
Try to blend in.
Blend in? What do you mean?
Blend in.
What are you saying?
- Too late.
- No, no. It's not too late!
I'm blending! I'm a blender!
Hey, calm down! What are you doing?
Stop moving!
Try not to look conspicuous.
- What are you doing?
- I'm blending.
- Go blend somewhere else.
- Don't distract me.
- No room at the inn.
- It's an art, not a science.
- Find your own hiding place.
- No, this is good.
Here she comes! You better run, Mojito!
- What? I thought you said, "Don't move."
- That was before. Now, you run.
Oh, hey. Proboscis.
Testy.
Please, no, please. I have vertigo!
My glands are swelling!
Please, no.
You! I'll kill you! You stupid lizard!
Get out of there.
I'm going to strangle your huevos!
Big bird! Big bird!
No, wait! Come back! I was just kidding!
- Come on, we're friends, right?
- I don't know you!
- Lizards, frogs...
- Find your own hiding place!
- We're practically related!
- No room at the inn!
- Come on, move over!
- You're not my friend!
I'll let you kiss my sister!
You son of a...
Where are your friends now, amigo?
Get your slimy-webbed phalanges
off my boots!
Sorry.
I got a bead on you, stranger.
So you get up real slow
lessen you want to spend the better part
of the afternoon
putting your face back together!
- No, ma'am, I don't.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
- I'm asking the questions here!
Our town is drying up.
We're in the middle of a drought.
Now someone's dumping water
in the desert!
It's a puzzle of undeterminable size
and dimension,
but I intend to find out
what role you playing in all this.
- Role?
- What are you involved in?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
I've got two one-acts, a mystery
and a musical I've been gestating.
I got the words, I'm just working on
the melody right now. It's like a...
I think it's gonna be a western.
A monkey got a cracker
His mother was a slapper
She'll be coming 'round the mountain
in the rain
You ain't from around here, are you?
I'm still working on it.
So, what's your name?
- Beans.
- That's a funny kind of name.
What can I say?
My daddy plumb loved baked beans.
Well, you're lucky
he didn't plumb love asparagus.
What are you saying?
I mean,
I enjoy a hearty puttanesca myself,
but I'm not sure that a child
would appreciate the moniker.
My daddy was a great man, even if
he did exhibit a proclivity for legumes.
- Spicy.
- You're eating his ashes!
You carry his remains?
No, his ashes. He loved to smoke.
They never found the body.
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons.
- What are you implying?
- Nothing.
My daddy was never near
that mine shaft.
He'd been sober for over a month!
And for you to insinuate that he would
abandon his parental responsibilities
at a delicate time in my personal
development is an affront to my sense...
Miss Beans?
Miss Beans? Hello?
Hello?
And until the people of Andromeda Five
return him safe and sound,
I will not sell my ranch!
- What... What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
- You're cuddling me.
- You were frozen.
- I was not.
Yes, you were. You stopped talking.
It's a defense mechanism.
Actually, lots of lizards have it.
You're making that up.
So, you gonna die out here,
or you want a ride into town?
No, no, no. Yeah. No. Yes, please.
Thank you. Sorry.
Today's Wednesday.
Wednesday's when we all get to it.
So who are you, really?
Well, I'm a man of many epithets.
There's my stage name, my pen name,
my avatar.
I had a pseudonym once,
but I had it legally changed.
And so the stranger,
seeking companionship,
finds the woman,
much like the sirens of ancient times
luring him to his certain demise.
...nom de plume, I have a CB handle.
I'm actually one of the few men
with a maiden name.
Whoa! Well, here we are.
Right.
Well, I sure do appreciate this,
Miss Beans,
- and if there's ever anything that I...
- Get on up!
Okay, then!
See you, Beans.
You heading out, Jim?
Well, we gave it our best shot.
We had to sell out.
Can't grow no crops without no water.
Bye, now!
What is it?
What was that for?
You're funny looking.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you're funny looking, too.
- That's a funny-looking shirt.
- That's a funny-looking dress.
- You got funny-looking eyes!
- You got a funny-looking face!
You're a stranger.
Strangers don't last long here.
Here's your beans, Beans.
I'm gonna need some more feed, too,
Willie.
Now, Beans, you owe me three quarts
already. I can't give you more credit.
But I'll have what I owe you at noon.
You don't understand. It's Mr. Merrimack
down at the bank. He cut off all credit.
Hey, Beans! Beans!
You know that there fella?
Hey, Beans! Miss Beans!
Nope.
Hey, Beans!
Hey.
Right. Blend in. Yeah, blend in.
I'd like a glass of water.
He wants a glass of water!
Make it a double!
Give him the spittoon!
Cactus juice. That's what we got.
Hey, there, fruit cup.
You're a long ways from home, ain't ya?
Who exactly are you?
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
What's the matter?
You missing your mommy's mangos?
As a matter of fact, I am.
But not as much as
your daddy's cooking!
Exactly where did you say
you were from?
Me? I'm from the West.
Out there, beyond the horizon.
Past the sunset.
The Far West.
Yeah, that's right, hombres.
The place I come from,
we kill a man before breakfast
just to work up an appetite.
Then we salt him, and we pepper him.
Then we braise him in clarified butter.
And then we eat him.
- You eat him?
- That's what I said!
Hell, I seen things make a grown man
lose control of his glandular functions!
You spend three days in a horse
carcass, living off your own juices.
It'll change a man. Oh, yeah.
Had a few extra aces in this deck,
gents. Just the way I like it.
So, no, my hirsute little rodent friend,
I am not from around these parts.
You might say I'm from everywhere
there's trouble brewing
and hell waiting to be raised.
You might say
I'm what hell's already raised up.
Name's
Rango.
Are you the fella
that killed them Jenkins brothers?
Killed them with one bullet.
Don't get no deader.
All seven of them?
That's right.
All seven of them.
Exactly how you do that, Mr. Rango?
You know, I'm glad you asked me that.
And I will be happy to tell you how.
But you're all gonna have to listen up!
Because this is where it gets
complicated.
That'll close out your account,
Mrs. Oats, two gulps and a swig.
Hands off, Mordecai! That's what's left
of your college education!
I don't rightly have
no other choice, Beans.
Times being so hard,
we just can't give no more credit.
But this here is a bank.
This is where you keep the water.
Beans, you've been like a niece to me
ever since your daddy
did not fall drunk down a mine shaft.
I've tried to protect you and others
from certain realities.
But that... Well...
- Mr. Merrimack?
- Realities are bearing down.
Mr. Merrimack!
Are you all right?
Beans, I need to show you something.
- That's all that's left?
- And this here is the reserve!
I don't know if you've noticed,
but folks just ain't making deposits
on a Wednesday no more!
Mr. Merrimack, if I don't get some water,
I'm gonna lose my ranch
and you're telling me
that's all that's left in the whole town?
Now that just don't make no sense.
Now, listen.
Someone is dumping water
in the desert.
I seen it with my own eyes.
Water in the desert?
Was this during
one of your special times?
No.
Well, we can all dream,
but this is the reality.
Why do you think so many people
are selling out? They just can't make it.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
Well, I suppose
we could talk to the Mayor.
I hear he's been helping people out
in this time of crisis.
The Mayor?
He may be our only hope.
Bullet hits a shovel, ricochets back
towards number three,
and that's when the roof caved in,
igniting the thermos
of pure grain alcohol
instantly vaporizing his bodily form,
leaving nothing but a charcoal statue
and a high-pitched squeal.
Hold on, there. That's only six.
What happened to number seven?
Number seven?
Hell, he died of infection.
- Seven men!
- One bullet!
Drinks all around!
Dance for me, Sod Buster!
- Yes, dance like a chicken!
- That's right! Dance!
You got corn in your ears, mate?
You don't pay the mortgage,
you don't own the land!
- That's basic real estate law, my friend.
- Quid pro quo!
If I see your face in this town again,
I'm gonna slice it off and use it
to wipe my unmentionables.
Mind the beak.
And don't come back!
What are you all gawping at?
Hey, Bad Bill,
there's something I got to tell you!
What is this?
You know who that is, Bill?
That there's Rango!
Yeah, he ain't afraid of you!
He ain't afraid of none of you.
Killed them Jenkins brothers.
- Done it with one bullet, Bill.
- All seven of them!
Is that right?
Let me get that before you...
No. Oh, I know. Here.
Just take care of that for you.
There. All better.
T.O. T.O. Just a second.
All right, now listen!
I'm going to give you fellas
one last chance to reconsider!
And if you don't want to reconsider
I might consider reconsidering myself.
Now that's what I'm talking about. Yeah.
All right, now listen up!
Things are going to be different
around here now that Rango's in town.
Got some new rules!
I want my shoes shined every morning,
my coffee hot, Danish on the side.
Whatever you do,
don't look me in the eye.
Stay out of my peripheral vision!
- It's Rango.
- What's he up to?
He ain't afraid of nobody.
He's telling that bird what's for!
And when you see me coming,
stand aside.
I take large steps and I don't want
none of you hayseeds
getting your bodily fluids on my boots!
Of course, there is no need for violence,
as long as we stick together,
work as a team.
So I want you all to come outside now
and line up single file
while I take a brief intermission!
What's he doing now?
I think it's a number two.
Never mind.
Take a look-see over here!
Well, look at him now!
He's chasing after that hawk!
Give him hell, Rango!
- Did you see that?
- He killed that thing!
What do you think, Doc?
This hawk is dead!
Shoot, I say we cook that right up.
He did it with one bullet!
Just like he said!
It's about time
we had a hero around here.
One who ain't in a pine box.
I think it's time he met the Mayor.
You hear that, Rango?
You're going to meet the Mayor!
Let's hear it for Rango!
And so the stranger basks
in the adulation of his new friends,
sinking deeper into the guacamole
of his own deception.
When is he going to die?
Soon, compadre. Soon.
My land is not for sale!
I came here to save my land, not sell it!
I'm sure there's something reasonable
we can work out if you just talk to him!
Beans! Where are you going? Beans?
The Mayor will see you now.
Water, Mr. Rango, water.
Without it,
there's nothing but dust and decay.
But with water there's life.
Look at them, so desperate to live,
they'll follow it anywhere.
That's the immutable law of the desert.
Control the water
and you control everything.
But I don't have to tell you that being
a true man of the West, as you are.
Oh, yeah. The West is the best.
This is from my private stock.
Vintage rainwater
from the Great Deluge.
Not Noah's deluge.
Good heavens, I'm not that old.
I guess power has its privileges.
You make a good point, son.
But with privilege comes responsibility.
Hell, I was mayor here
before there was a Dirt!
And I may be
just a sentimental old turtle
but I think there's a future for this town.
And I hope you'll be part of it.
- To Dirt!
- To Dirt.
You see them, Mr. Rango?
All my friends and neighbors?
It's a hard life here. Very hard.
Do you know how they make it through
each and every day?
They believe.
They believe it's going to be better.
They believe that the water will come.
They believe against all odds
and all evidence
that tomorrow will be better than today.
People have to believe in something.
Right now, they believe in you.
Pick it up, Mr. Rango.
Your destiny awaits.
People have to believe in something.
It's almost noon. Is everything ready?
Yeah. But he might be a problem.
He's not a problem, William.
He's a solution.
It just don't make no sense.
This whole town is drying up,
and the Mayor is the only one
who don't seem to be affected.
Doesn't that make you
just a wee bit suspicious?
And what about that water
I saw out in the desert?
All right! No need to incite anxiety.
I'll inquire about the Mayor.
But if you really feel
there's some conspiracy occurring,
I suggest you take it up
with the new sheriff.
This is going to be good. Hey!
Watch that needle there.
Not too tight.
I want to leave room for some pucker!
That's good.
Oh, easy there, tiger.
- A little up and back?
- I don't think so.
Have you got French cuffs with that?
Excuse me, Sheriff Rango.
I want to talk to you.
Hey, Beans,
what do you think of the new duds?
I got a 1 0-gallon hat
marked down from 15.
- That's nice.
- Have you met Angelique?
- Hello, Beans.
- Hello, Angelique.
- Tart.
- Floozy.
- Trollop.
- Excuse me, Mr. Rango.
I will blow that ugly right off your face!
I was just thinking that...
You want the old John Hancock,
do you?
- Well, here. Hold this.
- Sheriff Rango, this isn't a social call.
There's a bullet in there.
I know about the shindig this afternoon.
- I ordered myself some right fancy duds.
- Sheriff, I'd like to file a...
- Mr. Rango!
- Oh, you, too? No problem.
- Here, let me just...
- I need you to investigate...
You know, Beans, I bet you clean up
real nice, you put a little effort into it.
- What?
- Now, remember, son,
stay in school, eat your veggies,
burn everything but Shakespeare.
- Who's Shakespeare?
- Sheriff Rango,
if that is your real name.
I am trying to save my daddy's ranch,
which is on the verge
of an agricultural meltdown
while you're playing patty-cake
with this here trollop!
Sad, really. Such a drab little thing.
Why does she do that?
- It's a survival reflex.
- Her switch is just broken.
Well, that's an inconvenience.
It is not a rash! It is a birthmark!
I did it again, didn't I?
Did what?
Let me ask you something.
Did anybody here mention
what happened to our last sheriff?
Pardon, but may I ask you...
Excuse me, may I ask you...
The last sheriff... Pardon me.
Where is everybody going?
What exactly happened to the...
All day
I've faced the barren waste
Without the taste of water
Cool water
Old Dan and I
With throats burned dry
And souls that cry
For water
Cool
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Clear water
This is a heck of a hoedown
you got going.
Still working out those steps.
So, is this considered
normal civic behavior?
Every Wednesday, just like clockwork.
You kill bird.
Yeah. Matter of fact, I did.
Bird dead. Snake come.
Snake?
He means Rattlesnake Jake, Mr. Rango.
He never comes to town 'cause
he's scared of that hawk.
But he might come now.
Can I have your boots
when you're dead?
No!
And I ain't got no problem
with this Rattlesnake Jake.
That's just what Amos said.
Amos?
You got any gold fillings?
My fellow Dirtonians.
I welcome you to our great day
of deliverance. Hallelujah.
- Hallelujah!
Acolytes, prepare the holy spigot!
We have a newcomer
amongst us today, my friends.
A man I think needs
little introduction to you
so bold has been his entry
into our fair society.
Mr. Rango, would you step forward?
The time has come, my friends.
The time that was foretold!
- Hallelujah!
The sacred time!
The time of destiny!
- Hallelujah!
The time of deliverance!
It is the time of hydration!
- It's his fault!
- It's the newcomer!
- Burn him!
- He's a witch!
I get his boots!
My friends, my friends!
Temper your frustrations.
Times will be tough from now on.
Sacrifices will have to be made.
But if I can help in any way,
please know that my door is always...
Hold it, hold it!
Now, this whole thing
stinks three ways to Sunday.
First the bank's run dry
and now this here spigot?
The bank's run dry?
- What's she talking about?
- She said there's no water in the bank!
This is all we have!
We can't give it all out!
That was my rehydration account!
None of that civil disobedience
in my town, thank you very much.
Thank goodness you're here, Sheriff.
Things were getting out of hand.
Come right in.
Let me have a gander at the source
of the societal discontentment here.
Mercy.
All right, listen up! I've been thinking
and I believe I've figured something out.
You folks have a water problem!
Now just pay attention, everybody.
I'm trying to make a point here.
Let's say this fella here
were to take a drink of water.
Just one little drink.
No harm, no foul, right?
And you!
You're just as dried up and parched
as a jackrabbit in July.
So you belly on up
and take you a double shot!
Stay with me.
What do you think happens then?
Why we'd all be drinking!
And before you know it,
there wouldn't be any more water.
And then where would we be?
We'd be thirsty.
Real thirsty.
We'd turn on each other
like a bunch of animals!
Now look here.
We have got six days of water.
We have got five days...
As long as we've got water,
we've got ourselves a town.
Sheriff Rango is right.
As long as we have this water,
we have some hope.
And you can all take it from me.
My 100% full-time employment
from this moment on
will be to protect
our precious natural resource.
Ain't no one gonna tango
with the Rango.
Evening, ladies.
Evening, Sheriff.
And don't you come back!
Hold on there, Gordy. You get back
in there and you assert yourself,
and I think you'll find the people of this
here town to be surprisingly hospitable.
Thank you, Sheriff.
What? Not you again!
I stand corrected.
- This ain't the bank.
- I told you, Jedidiah!
Hold it right there!
- Who's that?
- It's the Sheriff!
Get them hands up
where I can see them!
Just as I suspected.
Prospecting without the authorized
equipment. Don't move a muscle.
Prospecting?
Now, you got your shovel,
pickaxe, Benadryl, loofah,
assorted snacks, some puzzle books
and you're gonna need a permit.
- Loofah.
- Ezekiel, Jedidiah!
What the Sam Hill's going on up there?
I've had polyps removed
smarter than the two of you!
Hell's fire, this ain't the bank!
Pappy, the Sheriff is standing right here,
helping us out.
Gonna give us a permit for prospecting.
That's right, sir. Just doing my duty.
The lonely constable on his rounds,
keeping an eagle eye out
for mayhem and malfeasance.
Does he look like he sounds?
Well, Sheriff,
if we was to hit the mother lode,
being prospectors and such,
where would we deposit said annuity?
Here in the town of Dirt,
we happen to have
the finest financial institution
this side of the Missouri.
Protected morning, noon and night
by yours truly.
Much obliged.
The bank's been robbed!
Good Lord, the bank's been robbed!
What's going on?
- It's gone! The water's all gone!
- What'd he say?
He said the bank's been robbed!
Dr. Marx! I'm on fire! Embrace me!
The bank's been robbed, the town is dry
"We'll die of thirst," the people cry
He promised to protect the vault
The water's gone, it's all his fault
All right, folks, stand back,
clear the area.
This is a crime scene now.
Secure the perimeter, dust for prints,
check for fibers, scan for DNA.
I want a urine sample from everyone.
And get me a latte.
And don't mix up the two.
What's this?
"Prospecting Permit."
I'll take that. Material evidence.
What are we gonna do now, Sheriff?
- We need that water.
- We're all going to die!
My friends, we all know
what we have to do now.
That's right.
We all know what we have to do now.
- And that would be?
- Form a posse.
Form a possum!
A posse.
Now, we're gonna be doing this
in an orderly fashion.
First off, does anybody here know
how to use a firearm of any kind?
All right, then.
What do we do now, Sheriff?
Now we ride!
Where are we going?
What?
Now, as my deputy, you'll be in charge
of all tracking and finding of villains,
utilizing your well-developed
Injun-uity, no offense taken.
So which way do you think they went?
You want to sniff the air or commune
with a buffalo or something?
Oh, you're good.
I'm depending on you, Spoons.
You got a little tobaccy
in the beard there.
Always good to have a medical man
along, Doc.
Reptiles got to stick together, right,
my brother?
I'm an amphibian.
Ain't no shame in that.
You sure you're
fit for duty there, soldier?
Well, you got a little something
in your eye there.
Oh, that? That there's conjunctivitis, sir.
It's hereditary.
Well, I'm glad to hear
it's not contagious.
Now, just wait a cotton-picking minute!
A posse ain't no place for a...
Never mind.
Hold on there, little sister.
Someone's gonna have
to look after the town while I'm gone.
Can I gut-shoot someone?
Let's put a pin in that.
Sheriff, you're going to bring
that water back, aren't you?
Count on it, little sister.
- Which way do we go, Sheriff?
- There's tunnels everywhere.
Whole town's perforated with them.
She got more holes in her
than a painted lady on a porcupine.
Hey, my daddy took me to her place.
Not what I expected.
How'd them fellers
find the bank, anyway?
Gentlemen, if we can just
stay on task here.
Sheriff! Over here!
- Would you look at that?
- Like seeing the face of God.
Amen, brother.
I remember when it used to flow
every Wednesday.
Those were the halcyon days.
Must be a reason she quit on us.
Whatever the reason,
something is controlling this here water.
What do you say, Sheriff?
Clearly, the robbers came
from this direction.
I say we track this pipe
back to its hydraulic origin
and apprehend the culprits
behind this aquatic conundrum.
- What'd he say?
- I think he said follow the pipe.
- He said follow the pipe.
Sure is humid down here.
Yeah, it's activating my piles.
I had a goitre removed once.
Looked like Tony Bennett
stepping out of the shower.
Shoot, I put that on a tortilla.
Whatever you do, do not look down.
- What is this place?
- It's an aquifer.
What's an aquifer?
Well, it's for aqua.
Well, it's empty now.
That's a big one.
- It's the end of the line.
- Don't go no further.
Well, now that there is a pipe.
It's got to be connected to something.
You talk too much.
Why don't you put a cork in it?
Why don't you put a cork...
Tell you where the sun don't shine.
Your mama did.
I'll cook her right up.
You two just don't get it, do you?
Someone or something
is messing with our hydration
and that pipe
has got something to do with it.
I thought
we was following bank robbers!
We're experiencing a paradigm shift.
I'm gonna shift the features on your face
if you don't shut up!
Go ahead and try!
Quiet, you savages! Stop your rattling.
You're affecting my cogitation.
Whoa! I got it. Snuff out them torches.
Sure enough.
Smart thinking there, feller.
- Start climbing.
- Get your foot out of my face!
Not bad, huh, Beans?
You keep thinking like that,
your hat's gonna catch on fire.
Well, you know, you get on a roll,
you just...
Hot, hot! Burn.
Poor things.
All they wanted was a little water.
Cactus dying of thirst. It don't bode well.
- Hey, look what I found!
- What you got there?
- I saw that first!
- Hey, that's mine!
Give me that!
It's empty anyway.
I knew that.
Where'd you find that?
Sheriff! You're going to want to see this!
It's Mr. Merrimack from the bank.
What's he doing here?
- Everybody stand back.
- All right, let me see.
Looks like them varmints shot him
in the back.
No, this man wasn't shot.
He was drowned!
- Drowned?
- In the middle of the desert?
What a way to go.
Well, now, whose boot prints are those?
That's interesting.
The ground's still wet.
I suppose we should bury him.
I don't know. Birds got to eat, too.
Circle of life!
Sheriff.
Will you say a few words?
Yeah. Yeah.
Dearly beloved.
We are gathered here today
to honor this man.
Mr. Merrimack,
you have the right to remain silent.
Speak now or forever hold your peace.
Amen.
- Amen.
Hey! What's that dad-gum Indian doing?
I see you're consulting with the spirits.
No, I'm moulting.
Means I'm ready to mate.
I'll keep that in mind.
Cactus fruit.
Ah, yes. The ancient cactus fruit.
I believe your people use it
as seasoning
when preparing your native dishes.
Also natural laxative.
Pick up trail.
Three men heading west.
One blind, one with
enlarged prostate, riding sidesaddle.
- What did he say?
- They're riding sidesaddle.
- We're whispering.
- What'd he say?
Someone's got a bad valve.
All right, which one of you fellers
needs a check-up?
Awkward.
What exactly are we going to do now?
Now we ride!
That means we're riding now!
This moment.
Marshmallows remind me
of going camping with my daddy.
I could eat them all night long.
Of course he did make me cough them
back up again for breakfast.
This one time,
I coughed up an entire Dalmatian.
That ain't nothing.
I coughed up a whole tribe of pygmies.
They started looking at me weird.
I remember them.
They was quite friendly.
I found a human spinal column
in my fecal matter once.
You might want to get that looked at.
Pass the beans, Beans.
- Sheriff?
- No, thanks.
Mr. Rango? Can you tell us
about the Spirit of the West?
- Yeah, tell us about that.
- Is it true what they say?
Yes, the Spirit of the West!
The eternally unattainable ideal.
They say he rides in
an alabaster carriage
with golden guardians to protect him.
But he only appears to those
who have undertaken an epic quest!
And have made it
to the other side.
The other side of what?
It's a metaphor.
My eye!
That's gonna heal right up.
Sheriff? What are you going to do
about Rattlesnake Jake?
What? Where?
Sorry about that. Word is
you come against him once or twice.
Yeah.
Jake. You mean my brother.
- Your brother?
- That's what I said!
But he's a snake and you're a lizard.
Well, Momma had an active social life.
Did he ever bite you?
Sure enough did. Look at that baby.
Go ahead, you can touch it.
That's interesting.
That there's a belly button.
Luckily, I'm immune to his venom.
Put some in my coffee
just to give it a little tang.
Is it true he's only scared
of them hawks?
Them's what we call
his natural predator.
All this talk of that serpentine devil
is putting my quills on edge!
I ain't sleeping tonight. No, sir.
Don't you all worry about a thing.
Come tomorrow, we'll locate that water
and return to a hero's welcome.
Friends, before we bunk down
I'd like us all to join hands
for a moment,
say a few words
to the Spirit of the West.
That's a good idea.
Ain't always spoken rightly to you,
Spirit of the West.
But tonight I want to thank you for
bringing Sheriff Rango into our lives.
It's a hard life we got.
Sometimes I don't know how
we're gonna make it.
But somehow, Sheriff Rango
makes me think we will.
We needed a brave man
and you sent us one.
Nice to have someone
to believe in again.
Thank you, Spirit of the West. Amen.
- Amen.
Just checking.
- It's a little cold tonight.
- Thank you.
You ever feel like those things
are looking at you?
That's a Spanish dagger.
But around here,
we just call them the Walking Cactus.
Walking?
There's an old legend they actually
walk across the desert to find water.
When I was a little girl, I'd stay up late
watching them, to see if they'd move.
I thought if I could follow them,
they'd lead me to someplace wonderful.
Someplace with enough water
for everyone.
Night after night, I watched them.
I never saw them move.
But you're still watching.
Who doesn't want to find
someplace wonderful?
We'll find the water, Beans.
I promise you.
That's such a lonely sound.
You ever get lonely?
Sometimes.
I can't imagine it. You're such a charmer
and everyone likes you so much.
- I never made friends easy like that.
- No?
No, we're pretty isolated
out there on the ranch,
sort of like being sealed up
in a little box.
Don't really see a lot of folks.
I wouldn't know what that's like.
There someone special
in your life, Rango?
There used to be.
But she couldn't keep her head.
Besides, my life's too dangerous
for that kind of thing.
You know, it's an awful solitary
existence out there on the prairie.
Riding the ranges and the suchlike.
Beans?
I'm gonna skin you alive, boy! I'm gonna
whup you like a red-headed stepchild!
Choleric varmints, ain't they?
Dysfunctional family. Need intervention.
What's that coming?
It's the water.
I have a plan, and each and every one
of you has a part to play.
What do I do?
Spoons, you got
the most important job of all.
You stay up here on the ridge,
and if anything goes wrong,
you give the signal.
Hey, Beans.
What size dress you wearing?
- He got it!
- Hallelujah!
- He found the water!
- You did it, son.
Well, actually...
Why can't you be all brainy
like your brother?
Pappy, about that water.
There's something I gots to tell you.
Hush up, now. Somebody's coming.
Good sirs, gracious good afternoon
to thee and thee and thee.
May I present Madame Lupone's
Terpsichorean Troupe
of Traveling Thespians!
- What is that?
- I think they's thespians.
Thespians?
That's illegal in seven states!
The stage is set. The princess
prepares to take her own life.
I yearn for love.
Meanwhile, the lone sentry
stands watch at the castle gate.
Stands watch at the castle gate...
Hark! Who goes there?
This plot is highly predictable.
Quiet! This is my favorite part.
Arriving to great fanfare
'twas her aged father,
strucketh by Cupid.
Prithee, unhand my fair daughter
and reach for the...
- Line?
- "Reach for the sky!"
What was that?
Must be that immersive theater.
We got you surrounded!
You and your entire family get
your hands up where I can see them.
My entire family?
Grits and spit and collard greens
Waffle chitlins, monkey brains
Refried bones and booger blood
Pickled eggs and flaps of mud
It's a full house.
Looks like we're gonna have ourselves
a good old-fashioned standoff.
I'll have you know, you're not looking
at our entire contingent.
What's that supposed to be?
That's the signal.
That's the signal!
Something must have gone wrong!
So something's supposed to happen?
I am open to suggestions.
Run!
Get on the wagon!
Should we have ourselves
some sport, chill'ens?
I likes it when they run.
Maybelle, give the holler!
Looks like we made it!
That audience was quite responsive.
Yeah, well, I think that
chromosome pool is about dried up.
We got bats!
Here! You drive.
Looks like there's gonna be
soup tonight!
Come on, let's get some!
What in tarnation?
Don't shoot the water!
Jedidiah! It's time for
the Alabama squeeze box!
Okay, Pa!
I am sensing hostility.
Incoming!
Hello!
Goodbye!
Lasso that swine!
I suggest we take evasive action!
I suggest you shut up and shoot!
- What happened to the Sheriff?
- He had a previous engagement!
Boseefus, give them some gumbo now!
What was that? Go check it out!
What is it? Is there a problem?
You could call it that.
Headache.
Is that all you got?
That wasn't altogether unpleasant!
Eat lead!
Here, hold these.
Get your hands off me!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Jump!
It's impossible.
It can't be. It's empty.
There's no water!
No water?
Then what the hell we been fighting for?
Sir, you have defiled and desecrated
the very sustenance of our livelihood!
I think that there fella in the purty dress
is the Sheriff.
That's the same fellow what give us
a prospecting permit?
- A what?
- Irrelevant! Obfuscation.
You and your kin are under arrest
for bank robbery
and the murder
of our beloved financial advisor
Johannes Merrimack the Third,
AKA, Fluffy Joe.
Sheriff, we didn't kill nobody.
We done tunneled into that vault,
but there weren't nothing in it.
Somebody done robbed that bank
before we robbed it.
Then where'd you get this here jug?
That's what I been trying
to tell you, Pappy.
I found it in the desert.
Then why in tarnation
did you bring it here?
Hold on! You're saying this here jug
was empty when you found it?
That's right.
I don't believe a word of it.
- Let's hang them, Sheriff!
- String them up!
Who'd dump water in the desert?
Wouldn't be the first time.
It's a puzzle!
It's like a big old mammogram!
What's going on, Sheriff?
I don't know.
But I'm going to strip away this mystery
and expose its private parts.
You and your kin are coming with me.
They're coming!
Here they come!
Looks like they got them robbers.
Where's the water?
There weren't no water.
Where is he going?
He's going to see the Mayor.
He's got to be pleased with that.
That's a good one, boss!
That's interesting.
I do apologise for the shoes, Mr. Rango,
but there's a certain protocol
to this game, you understand.
I'm a bit of a stickler for protocol.
Well, that's good, 'cause you got
a few questions to answer
and I've got my own protocol.
But why would anyone dump water
in the blooming desert?
It does seem a bit naive, taking the word
of admitted bank robbers.
Besides, once they hang,
your job is done.
- Bravo!
- Job well done.
But what if somebody did rob the bank
before they got there?
And who would do that, Mr. Rango?
I was hoping you could tell me.
That sounds marginally
near to an accusation.
Take it any way you like.
Something you said keeps rattling
around in my frontal lobe.
What's that?
"Control the water
and you control everything."
Come now, Mr. Rango.
You attribute divine power to me.
How on earth
could I possibly control the water?
You've obviously mastered this game.
Well, I've been playing it
for many years, sir.
I was here before the highway split
this great valley.
I watched the march of progress,
and I learned a thing or two.
Perhaps it's time you started
to take the long view,
begin to appreciate
the broad sweep of history.
Look out there, son.
You can almost see time passing.
What are you building out here?
The future, Mr. Rango, the future.
One day soon,
all this is going to fade into myth,
the frontier town, the lawman,
the gunslinger.
There's just no place
for them any more.
- We're civilized now.
- That's right, civilized.
That's what the future holds.
You can either be part of it,
or you can be left behind.
Is that what happened to
Mr. Merrimack? Did he get left behind?
Careful, Mr. Rango. You seem to forget
you're just one little lizard.
You seem to forget
I'm the law around these parts.
Our new sheriff has been
playing the hero for so long,
he's actually starting to believe it.
Call in Rattlesnake Jake.
But Jake's the Grim Reaper.
He never leaves
without taking a blooming soul.
Do it!
Now be still. You gotta look
presentable to meet your maker.
Death has arrived
How will the hero survive?
The Mayor has bought up
all the land in the valley,
except for your ranch, Miss Beans.
That just don't make no sense.
Without water, that land is useless.
Unless he controls the water.
Like a monkey's bladder!
Then he could bring it back
once he's bought up all the land.
But how does he control the water?
Well, you gotta spend some time
and train them.
'Cause you know monkeys, when
they do go, you rub their nose in it.
Sheriff, we got a problem.
Hold on, Beans.
That won't be necessary.
- Hang him till his head turns blue!
- Give us them robbers!
Hold on! Calm down, everyone!
Let me talk!
- Nail them to the courthouse!
- Now, calm down, everybody.
Get them out here
so we can cut off their giblets!
You, too, Spoons?
They done taken that water.
They taken everything we got!
No one's stringing anyone up.
Not while I'm sheriff.
But this is all his fault!
You said you's gonna
bring the water back.
It's just, we got no hope
without that water.
We got nothing left to believe in.
You see that sign up there?
As long as that sign says "Sheriff,"
you can believe that there's
law and order in this town.
But without law and order,
ruminate on that. Oh, yeah.
Starts out slow, like a fungus.
Somebody says a cross word.
Accusations start flying.
Neighbor turns on neighbor.
Pretty soon, we're eating our children!
And then dogs and cats
are getting together
to create all sorts of unnatural
mutant aberrations!
So, you want something
to believe in, Spoons?
Believe in me.
Believe in that there sign.
For as long as it hangs there,
we got hope.
Hello, brother.
Thirsty?
Long time, brother.
How you been keeping?
Well, you know...
I hear you been telling about how
you killed all them Jenkins brothers.
With one bullet, wasn't it?
Isn't that right?
All these good folks here
believe your little stories, don't they?
Why, they believe you're just
a stone killer, don't they?
Seems these folks trust you.
They think you're gonna save
their little town.
their little souls!
But we know better, don't we?
So why don't you show your friends here
what you're made of?
Show them who you really are.
Why don't you just pull your gun
and shoot me?
But, of course, you won't need all these.
Just one, right?
Go ahead, hero. Pull the trigger.
You got killer in your eyes, son?
I don't see it.
You didn't do any of them things
you said, did you?
You didn't kill them Jenkins brothers.
You ain't even from the West!
Are you?
- Say it!
- No.
Speak up.
I don't think your friends here heard you.
No.
All you've done is lie
to these good people.
You ain't nothing but a fake
and a coward. Isn't that right?
Yes.
- Louder!
- Yes.
Listen close, you pathetic fraud.
This is my town now.
If I ever see you again, I will take
your soul straight down to hell!
Who are you?
Who am I?
I'm nobody.
Golden guardians.
The alabaster carriage.
The Spirit of the West.
Excuse me? Mister Spirit, sir?
There's a beaut. Sometimes you got to
dig deep to find what you're looking for.
So you made it.
Is this heaven?
If it were, we'd be eating Pop-Tarts
with Kim Novak.
Yeah.
No kidding.
What are you doing out here?
Searching, same as you.
I don't even know
what I'm looking for any more.
I don't even know who I am.
They used to call you
the Man with No Name.
These days they got a name
for just about everything.
Doesn't matter what they call you.
It's the deeds make the man.
Yeah, but my deeds just made things
worse. I'm a fraud. I'm a phony!
My friends believed in me,
but they need some kind of hero.
Then be a hero.
No. No, no, you don't understand.
I'm not even supposed to be here.
That's right. You came a long way
to find something that isn't out here.
Don't you see? It's not about you.
It's about them.
But I can't go back.
Don't know that you got a choice, son.
No man can walk out on his own story.
So you made it.
That's right, amigo.
The other side of the road.
Did you just see that?
We each see what we need to see.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yeah.
It is.
Come, my friend.
I want to show you something.
Many years ago,
this entire valley was covered in agua.
Now only one question remains.
Where did it go?
They follow the water.
They follow the water! Come on!
That just don't make no sense.
Without water, that land is useless.
What are you building out here?
The future, Mr. Rango.
You can either be part of it,
or you can be left behind.
I was here before the highway split
this great valley.
I watched the march of progress
and I learned a thing or two.
Control the water
and you control everything.
Come now, Mr. Rango.
You attribute divine power to me.
How on earth
could I possibly control the water?
What now, amigo?
No man can walk out on his own story.
I'm going back.
But why?
Because that's who I am.
You got a lot of nerve showing up here,
lawman. What is it you want?
Your pappy and them boys are about
to hang for something they didn't do.
But I've got a plan.
I appreciate how difficult
this is for you, Beans.
But you're making a practical decision.
Decisions, decisions.
There's no need for any more suffering.
Your family's ranch is nothing
but a wasteland now.
Sign the deed and relieve yourself
of your father's burden.
My daddy was not a burden!
Keep your blood money
and I'll keep my land!
Do what he says or,
by all the fires of the black pit,
I'll squeeze them pretty brown eyes
out of your skull!
Now, hold on, Jake.
There's no need to...
Let me do my job! You brought me in.
Now we're gonna play this thing
out to the end!
Sign the damn paper, woman!
Go to hell!
Where do you think I come from?
Look into my eyes.
I want to see you die.
Jake!
I'm calling you out!
This day
just got a little more interesting.
Put her down.
Or what, little man?
You going to kill me?
That's just about the size of it.
- Get your filthy paws off me!
- Shut your gob!
All right, Sheriff, make your move.
Now amigos!
- Heave! Heave!
That was a bad idea.
Thirsty, brother?
Here it comes!
No. No!
It's a miracle!
Look out!
- Lookee there!
- What is that?
It's our salvation, Pa!
It's a jailbreak, boys! We're busting out!
I'm gonna blow so many holes in you,
your guts'll be leaking lead!
Well, then
it's a good thing I brought some backup.
What?
Ain't no hawk.
Ain't nothing but bats!
Stick to the plan, boys!
Let's bleed that devil dry!
It only takes one bullet.
You ain't got the nerve.
Try me.
Oh, Mr. Rango.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Hand me your gun, Sheriff.
Now, Mr. Rango.
Beans! Hold on.
Don't worry, I got a plan.
Help!
Open the door!
Okay, plan B.
Beans, you're mumbling.
All my problems taken care of
except for one.
It's a new West, Jake.
There's no room for gunslingers
any more. We're businessmen now.
Yeah, we got new hats.
Where I come from,
we call this improvisation.
You came back.
What was that?
No need to panic,
but I think you just swallowed plan B.
What?
Okay, panic time.
You and the Sheriff are more alike
than you think.
You're nothing but legends.
Pretty soon,
no one will believe you even existed.
One last bullet to kill one last outlaw.
How fitting.
Sheriff, I'm sure if we work together,
we can reach a mutually beneficial
solution to our current situation.
You better take it up with him.
One bullet.
I tip my hat to you,
one legend to another.
What was that you said?
"Pretty soon,
no one will believe you even existed."
No, Jake! No!
Rango!
You brought the water back,
just like you promised.
You really are a hero.
Well, the thing about heroes is,
whenever you...
Don't spoil it.
Right.
Well, I don't know about you all,
but I could sure go for a dip.
And so the lizard completes his journey
from humble beginnings
to the legend we sing of today.
And although he is certain to die,
perhaps from a household accident,
which account
for 65% of all unnatural deaths,
the people of the village
will honor his memory
even as they abandon their dignity.
- I'm going in.
- How about a cold one, there?
Water ain't money. Money is money.
- Well, I ain't got no...
- We're talking hard cash.
We have a problem.
Who let Snuggles in the pool again?
I really think you complete me.
Prithee, unhand my fair maiden.
- Cut. Cut. Everybody, take five.
- How can you keep missing your mark?
What's my motivation?
Oh, you kids.
What did you do that for?
I was just checking.
I hear if you get too sunburnt,
you can peel a man's face right off.
- What is it?
- That there's some human spleen.
Don't touch it.
That's the second time
that's happened to me.
This water thing's great.
I'm urinating right now.
Adult swim, next five minutes.
Stay between the buoys.
I packed your lunch. Danish is in there
and I picked the raisins out
just the way you like it.
Don't forget, your nasal spray is
in your saddle-bag...
- Beans!
- ...and your moisturizing lotion...
- Now, Beans! We've talked about this.
- Lotion?
That's for my gun. That's gun lotion.
Sheriff, where are you headed?
There's trouble down a dry creek.
Bad Bill's been acting up again.
Now, honey, you come back
with all your digits.
And don't go trying to be a hero.
Beans, you are missing the point.
I got an image to protect now.
Where's my Tic Tacs?
- I found them.
- What's going on?
Well, in order to satisfy the needs
of the collective,
the hero must abandon the self
and solidify his image as an icon
that will forever be remembered.
So, this is the sunset shot.
Give them a good one, amigo.
Ready, Excelsior?
My fellow comrades.
There will be times
when you doubt yourself.
When you feel pummeled
by the cataclysms of life,
remember this moment.
Remember me.
Know that I will be there watching you,
sometimes at inappropriate moments.
That's part of the deal.
And remember, within all of us resides
the true Spirit of the...
Let's take it from the top.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
( رانغو )
إجتمعنا هنا اليوم لنُخلـّدَ في أغنيةٍ
.الحياة و الممات قبل الأوان لإسطورةٍ عظيمة
.(رانغو) -
.لذا اجلسوا، استرخوا -
و استمتعوا بالفوشار و الحلويات
،قليلةِ السعرات
بينما نقصّ عليكم الحكاية الغريبة و المحيّرة
.للبطل الذي لم ينضمّ بعدُ لقصّته الخاصّة
مقرمش - مدهن - مخبوز
.مشمّع - محلّى
!هيّا بنا جميعاً
.من البداية
.المسرح جاهز
.الليل عابقٌ بالتوجّس
وحيدةً في حجرتها، تستعدّ
.الأميرةُ لإزهاقِ روحها
من الأفضل أن يكون جسدي طعاماً للديدان
!على أن أعيش دون حبّ
.تناولتْ كأسَ السمّ
في هذه الأثناء، كان الشرّيرُ
.مالفوليو) يتآمرُ لاعتلاء العرش)
بينما يستلقي والدها العجوز
.مريضاً للغاية
...نعم، أنا مريضٌ للغاية
هارك)، من هناك؟)
هذا أنا! البطل المتوقـّع العائد
.لإنقاذ فتاته غير المستقرّة عاطفيّاً
،حرّروها يا سجّاني الفضيلة
!أو ذوقوا اللدغةَ المريرةَ لإنتقامي
...لدغة... اللد
،(د. (ماركس)؟ د. (ماركس
!لا يصلني شيءٌ منك
!ناقشنا هذا يا رفاق
.التمثيل تفاعل
!فيكتور)، أنتَ خشبيّ)
.ها قد قلتُها
.سيّد (تيمز)، كنتَ جيّداً
!ربّما أكثر من اللازم
ماذا قلت يا ( فيكتور) ؟
!شخصيّتي غير محدّدة؟ هذا سخيف
...أعلمُ من أكون. أنا الـ
!أنا الفتى! النصير، البطل
كلّ قصّة تحتاج لبطل! أعني من أفضل منّي
لينتشي بتملّق رفاقه الكثر؟
.المسرحُ جاهز
.و الجمهور متعطّشٌ لمغامرة
من أنا؟
!يمكن أن أكون أيّاً كان
يمكن أن أكون قبطاناً بحريّاً عائداً
!من رحلة هائلة لإسترداد ذراعه الآليّة
أو عالم إنسانيّات خبيثاً يحارب
!"الثعابين في "الكونغو
!"مُت يا "تشونغا
!مُت
،و إن كنتم ترغبون بالرومانسيّة
!فيمكن أن أكون أعظمَ عاشق عرفه العالم
!مرحباً
لم أستطع تجنّب ملاحظتكِ تلاحظين
.أنيّ ألاحظكِ
فكما تعرفين، تجدني النساءُ
.وسيماً على نحو ٍ مزعج
.لكن لا يبدو أنّكِ كذلك
...توقفي! لا، فعلاً
! حسناً، إن كان لابدّ
!ماذا تفعلين؟ هذا يدغدغ
أهذان حقيقيّان؟
!تلك هي. الصراع
.كنتَ محقّاً (فيكتور). لم أكن محدّداً
!يا قوم، جاءتني رؤيا
.لا يمكن أن يتواجد البطل في فراغ
ما تحتاجه قصّتنا، هو حدثٌ ساخرٌ
.غيرُ متوقـّع، يدفع البطلَ إلى صراع
!!!! (ديفيد)
سيّد (تيمز)؟
!هذا صحيح، أنت
.لا تكن خجولاً. إقترب
.لا بأس
.أحسنت
...إقترب أكثر
.جيّد
.لن أعضّك
.أحتاجُ لبعض المساعدة هنا -
هل... هل أنتَ على ما يرام؟ -
.يجب أن أصل للطرف الآخر
الطرف الآخر؟ أتعني أنّكَ أنتَ الذي كنتَ
...تعبر الطريق؟ لهذا حدث
!لمَ فعلتَ ذلك؟ -
.هذا مسعاي. إنّه بإنتظاري -
أيـ...؟ ماذا؟ من؟ -
.روح الغرب يا صديقي -
المختار) ، يقولون أنّه يركبُ عربةً من)
المرمر و الحرّاس الذهبيّون يحمونه
عمّ... عمّ تتحدّث؟ -
.التنوير. نحن نكرة من دونه -
!نكرة؟! مسعاك الوهميّ دمّر حياتي
!كانت لديّ شبكة علاقاتٍ هائلة
!أصدقاء محنّكون للغاية! كنتُ مشهوراً جدّاً
.أصدقاء؟ لا أرى أيّ أصدقاء -
...حسناً -
!أنتَ سحليّةٌ وحيدٌ جدّاً
.إسمع، أحتاج ماءً، رطوبة
.أسناني متشقّقة
.أحتاج مستحضراً للبشرة
.لقد خسرتُ طبقةً جلديّة فعلاً
.قريباً سأرى أعضائي الداخليّة
.كما يحدث عندك هناك
،إسمع، لا أستطيع البقاءَ في الصحراء
.مفهوم؟ لا أنتمي لهذا المكان
.قد يكون ذلك صحيحاً
.لكن ها أنت ذا
، و الآن... ساعدني على النهوض
. و سأساعدكَ لتجد ما تريد
ستساعدني؟ -
.ربّما أكثر. أسرع. يجب أن أعودَ لمسعاي -
أتعني أنّكَ فعلتَ هذا من قبل؟ -
.نعم. مرّاتٍ كثيرة، أجل -
.إقترب. حسناً... يكفي
.إجذب إصبعي
.الروح بإنتظاري
...حسناً. حسناً
.حسناً! هذا لن يُجدي -
.يجب أن أصل للطرف الآخر -
لمَ لا تنتظر حتّى يخلو الطريق
من السيّارات؟
...الأمر ليس سهلاً كما يبدو عليه -
ماذا؟ -
.إنّه تعبيرٌ مجازيّ
!ثمّة واحدٌ آخر
!كنتُ أعلمُ ذلك
أتحتاجُ لمساعدة يا صديقي؟ -
.أظنّ التعبيرَ المجازيّ سحقَ طحالي -
.دربُ المعرفة مشحونٌ بالعقبات -
.نعم... أنا أبحثُ عن دربِ الماء و حسب -
إن أردتَ إيجاد الماء، فعليكَ
."أوّلاً أن تجدَ "ديرت = التراب
ديرت"؟"
.الأقدارُ رحيمةٌ بك
.غداً الأربعاء، ستأتي المياه
عندَ الظهيرة، سيتجمّع سكّان المدينة
...من أجلِ طقسٍ غامض
ماذا؟... بلدة؟
أناسٌ حقيقيّون و كلّ شيء؟ أين؟
.على بُعدِ مسيرة يوم
.إتبع ظلّك
أتريدني أن أهيمَ في الصحراء ببساطة؟ -
.ذاك هو الطريق -
،حسناً. فأنتَ تقولُ أنّ هناك بلدة
بلدة حقيقيّة؟ لا كتعبيرٍ مجازيّ؟
.إذهب. لا عليك -
.حسناً. ها أنا ذا ذاهب -
!سأغادر الطريق، الآن
!أنا أسير... في ... الصحراء، وحيداً
!لكلٍّ منّا رحلتُه الخاصّة
...سأراك على الطرف الآخر
أهلاً بكَ صديقي *
* إلى أرضٍ بلا نهاية *
* الصحراء و الموت، الأقربُ كأصدقاء *
* نُنشد شجاعته بهذه الأغنية البهيجة *
* انتبهوا أكثر، فلن يطول وجوده هنا *
* بينما تقتلع الطيور عينيه *
* و تقصّر الشمسُ عظامه *
* سيرى أحشاءه مبعثرةً *
* و يرى كيف يخسر خصيتيه *
هنا في صحراء "موهافي"، إستغرقت الحيوانات
.ملايين السنوات لتتأقلم مع البيئة القاسية
...أمّا بالنسبة لسحليّة
.فسيموت
...منذ 4 أجيالٍ و 7 سنوات... جلبَ آباؤنا -
!لا تتحرّك -
ماذا؟
!لستُ أتحرّك -
.لستُ أتحرّك -
.حاول أن تموّه نفسك -
ماذا؟ تمويه؟ ما الذي تعنيه؟
!موّه نفسك -
ماذا؟ ما الذي تقوله؟ -
.فات الأوان -
!لا! لا! لم يفت الأوان! أنا أموّه نفسي! أنا مموّه -
اهدأ! ما الذي تفعله؟
!كفّ عن التحرّك
.حاول ألاّ تظهرَ بوضوح
أنت! ما الذي تفعله؟
.أموّه نفسي -
.اذهب و موّه نفسكَ في مكانٍ آخر -
!لا تشتّت انتباهي -
!لا يوجدُ متّسعٌ هنا -
!إنّه فنٌّ و ليس علماً -
!جد مكانكَ الخاصّ للإختباء -
.هنا جيّد -
.ها هيَ قادمة. يجدرُ بك أن تركض يا رفيقي -
."هو ، ماذا؟ لكنّك قلتَ "لا تتحرّك -
!هذا سابقاً. أمّا الآن... اركض -
.أحمق يا صديقي
.مرحباً! تحتاج خرطوماً
.لذيذ
!لا
!رجاءً! رجاءً لا! رجاءً لا
!لديّ دوار! غددي منتفخة
...رجاءً لا
!ربّاه
!أنت! سأقتلكَ أيّها السحليّة الأحمق
!أخرج من هناك! سأقتلع خصيتيك
!طائرٌ كبير
! لا، لا، مهلاً! عد! كنتُ أمزح ، هيّا
نحن أصدقاء، صح؟ -
.أنا لا أعرفك -
.سحالي، ضفادع، نحن متقاربون عمليّاً -
!إبحث عن مكانك الخاصّ للإختباء -
!هيّا، ابتعد
!إنك لست صديقي -
!سأسمح لكَ أن تقبّل شقيقتي -
!لا ، لا
...يا ابن الـ
أين أصدقاؤك الآن يا صديقي؟
!أبعد يديكَ الغشائيّتين المخاطيّتين عن جزمتي
.آسف -
.أنا أصوّب عليك. إنهض ببطء ٍ شديد -
إلا ّ إن أردتَ تمضية الظهيرة
!بإعادة جمع وجهك
.لا، لا يا سيّدتي. لا أريد -
من أنت؟ -
من أنا؟ -
!أنا من يطرح الأسئلة هنا -
بلدتنا تجفّ و نحن في منتصف فصل الجفاف الآن
.و أحدهم يسكبُ الماءَ في الصحراء
أفترضُ أنّه أمرٌ غير محدّد، لكنّي أنوي
.معرفةَ الدور الذي تلعبه في كلّ ما يحصل
دور؟ -
بماذا أنتَ متورّط؟ -
،حسناً، مسرورٌ لسؤالك. لديّ دوران
.الغامض و الموسيقيّ كنتُ أؤدّيهما
لديّ الكلمات، و كنتُ أعملُ على
...اللحن الآن. إنّه مثل
.أظنّه سيكون غربيّاً
* حصل القرد على كعكة *
* و أمّه كانت قاسية *
* ستأتي من خلف الجبل *
* تحت المطر *
لستَ من هنا، أليس كذلك؟
.ما زلتُ أقوم بتحسينها
فما اسمكِ إذاً؟
.(بينز = فاصولياء) -
.هذا اسمٌ مضحكٌ نوعاً ما -
ماذا بوسعي أن أقول؟
.أبي (بلم = إجاص) كان يحبّ الفاصولياء المعلّبة
.حسناً، أنتِ محظوظةٌ لأنّه لم يكن يحبّ الهليون -
ما الذي تعنيه؟ -
أعني أنّي أتمتّع بشوربة الهليون، لكن لا أعتقد
.أنّ الأطفال يستلطفون الألقاب
،كان والدي رجلاً جيّداً
.حتّى لو أنّه كان يُظهر ميله إلى قرون النبات
.بطعم التوابل -
!أنتَ تأكل رماده -
تحملين رميمه؟ -
.لا! بل رماده. كان يحبّ التدخين -
.لم يجدوا جثـّته قط -
.لا بدّ أنّ له أسبابه -
إلامَ تُلمّح؟ -
.لا شيء -
.لم يقترب والدي من الشراب قط
.كان متوقـّفاً عن الشرب لأكثر من شهر
و إن كنتَ تلمّح إلى أنّه ترك مسؤوليّاته الأبويّة
...في مرحلةٍ حسّاسةٍ من تطوّر شخصيّتي
آنسة (بينز)؟
مرحباً؟
و إلى أن يعود سكّان "آندروميدا 5" سليمين
!معافين، لن أبيع مزرعتي
ماذا؟ -
ماذا؟ ما الذي تفعلينه؟ -
ما الذي تفعله؟ -
ما الذي أفعله أنا؟ -
.كنتَ تحضنني -
.أصابكِ الجمود -
.لا، غيرُ صحيح -
.بلى. توقّفتِ عن الكلام -
.إنّها آليّةٌ دفاعيّة
.و الكثيرون يمتلكونها في الواقع
!أنتِ إخترعتِ ذلك
،فهل تريدُ الموتَ هنا إذاً
أم تريد توصيلةً إلى المدينة؟
!لا! لا! لا!... بلى! لا
.نعم من فضلك! شكراً لكِ
.آسف
.اليوم هو الأربعاء
.و يومَ الأربعاء نذهبُ جميعاً إليها
فمن أنتَ حقّاً؟ -
.حسناً، أنا رجلٌ متعدّد الصفات -
.لديّ اسمٌ لمسرحي، لأدبي، أفاتاري
.كان لديّ اسمٌ مستعار، لكنّي غيّرته قانونيّاً
،و هكذا الغريبُ الباحثُ عن رفقة
.يجدُ امرأةً
.تماماً كجنيّات البحر في العصور الغابرة
.تغريه نحو حتفه المحتوم
اسمٌ مستعارٌ، اسمٌ كوميديّ، كما أنّي
!من القلائل الذين لهم اسمٌ أوسط
.ها قد وصلنا
صحيح. حسناً، أقدّر لكِ
...هذا يا آنسة (بينز). و إن كان بإمكاني
!انطلق
.حسناً إذاً
.(آراكِ لاحقاً... (بينز
."أهلاً بكم في "ديرت
ستتركنا يا (جيم)؟ -
.حسناً، لقد يئسنا من ذاك الدكّان -
.علينا أن نبيعه
.لا يأتيني زبائن لعدمِ وجود الماء
!وداعاً
ما الأمر؟
لم فعلتم هذا؟ -
.مظهركَ غريب -
.حقّاً؟ مظهركِ غريبٌ أيضاً -
.شكل هذا القميص غريب -
!ذاكَ فستانٌ غريب -
!لديكَ عينان غريبتان -
!لديكِ وجهٌ غريب
.أنتَ غريب
.و الغرباء لا يستمرّون طويلاً هنا
.(تفضّلي الفاصولياء (بينز -
.(سأحتاجُ المزيد من الطعام أيضاً (ويلي -
.(أنتِ مدينةٌ لي بثلاثة كوارتات يا (بينز
.لا أستطيعُ إقراضكِ أكثر
.لكنّي سأسدّد ديني عند الظهيرة -
.لستِ تفهمين -
،السيّد (ميرماك) من المصرف
.هو الذي قطع كلّ الإعتمادات
بينز)؟)
أتعرفين ذاكَ الفتى؟ -
.بينز)، هذا أنا) -
.لا -
!(بينز) -
!صحيح. أندمج
.أندمج
.أريدُ كأس ماء
!يريد كأس ماء
!إجعله مزدوجاً -
!أعطِه المبصقة -
.عصير صبّار، هذا كلّ ما لدينا
.يا كوبَ الفواكه
أنتَ بعيدٌ جدّاً عن ديارك، أليس كذلك؟
من تكون بالتحديد؟
من أنا؟
.أستطيع أن أكون أيّ أحد
ما الخطب؟
إشتقتَ لمانغو والدتك؟
.في الحقيقة، نعم
لكن ليس بقدر إشتياقي
!لطهو والدك
بالضبط. من أين أنت؟ -
أنا؟ -
.أنا من الغرب. هناك، خلف الأفق
.ما وراء الغروب
.الغرب البعيد
.هذا صحيحٌ يا شباب
من حيث أتيت، نقتلُ شخصاً
!قبل الإفطار، فقط لنفتح شهيّتنا
نُملّحه، نتبّله، نطهوه في
.زبدةٍ صافية، ثمّ نأكله
تأكلونه؟ -
!هذا ما قلتُه -
رأيتُ أموراً تجعلُ الناضجَ
.يفقدُ السيطرةَ على وظائف غدده
إمضاء ثلاثة أيّامٍ في جثّةِ حصانٍ
،دون شرب شيء
!هذا يغيّر الرجل
.نعم
توجد بضعة آسات إضافيّة في ورق
.اللعب هذا، صح؟ تماماً كما أحبّها
لا إذاً يا صديقي القارض الصغير
.مُطلق الإبر، لستُ من هذه الأرجاء
يمكنكَ القولُ أنّي من كلّ مكانٍ
.تعمّه المشاكل و تنتظر الجحيم أن تشبّ فيه
يمكنكَ القول أنّي أنا الذي
!ربّاه الجحيم
...اسمي
.(رانغو)
!(رانغو)
أأنتَ من قتل الأخوة (جينكنز)؟
.نعم، قتلتهم برصاصةٍ واحدة
.ماتوا و شبعوا موتاً
السبعة كلّهم؟
.هذا صحيح
.السبعة كلّهم
و كيف بالضبط فعلتَ ذلك
يا سيّد (رانغو)؟
.أوَ تعلم، سعيدٌ لسؤالك
!و يسرّني أن أخبركم كيف
،لكن عليكم جميعاً أن تُصغوا
...لأنّ الأمور هنا تبدأ تصبح
.معقّدة
.(هذا كلّ حسابك يا سيّدة (أوتس
.جرعتان و رشفة
،(أبعد يديكَ (مورديكاو
!هذا ما بقي من تعليمكَ الجامعيّ
.(لا أملكُ خياراً آخر يا آنسة (بينز
أصبحت الأوقات عصيبةً
.و لا يمكننا تأمين إعتمادات أخرى
!لكن هنا المصرف
.هنا تحتفظون بالماء
...نحتفظ بالماء
بينز)، لطالما كنتِ بمثابةِ ابنة أخي)
...منذ ٌأنّ والدكِ
.لم يسقط ثملاً تحت عمود المنجم
حاولتُ حمايتكِ و حمايةَ آخرين
.من وقائعَ محدّدة
...لكن... حسناً -
سيّد (ميرماك)؟ -
.وقائع صعبة -
أأنتَ على ما يرام؟
.بينز)، يجب أن أُريكِ شيئاً)
أهذا كلّ ما بقي؟ -
!وهذا هو الإحتياطيّ -
لا أعرف إن لاحظتِ، لكن لم يعد الناس
.يضعون إيداعات أيّام الأربعاء
،سيّد (ميرماك)، ما لم أحصل على ماءٍ أكثر
،فسأخسر مزرعتي
و تقول أنّ هذا كلّ ما بقي في
البلدةِ كلّها؟
.هذا غير منطقيّ
.إسمع، أحدهم يهدر الماء في الصحراء
!رأيتُ هذا بأمّ عيني
!ماءٌ في الصحراء
أكان هذا خلال واحدٍ من... أوقاتكِ الخاصّة؟
.لا -
.حسناً، نستطيع أن نحلم. لكن هذا هو الواقع -
لماذا الكثيرون برأيكِ يبيعون؟
.لأنّهم لا يستطيعون الإستمرار
حسناً... ما عسايَ أفعل؟
.حسناً، أعتقدُ بإمكاننا التحدّث مع رئيس البلدية
.فقد سمعتُ أنّه يساعد الناس في هذه الأزمة
رئيس البلديّة؟ -
.قد يكون أملنا الوحيد -
ضربت الرصاصة المجرفة و إرتدّتْ على الثالث
،و عندها تقطـّر من السقف كحولٌ أخضرُ صافٍ
فتبخّر جسمه فوراً إلى لا شيء سوى
.تمثالٍ فحمٍ متصلـّب
،إنتظر عندك، هؤلاء ستّة فقط
ماذا حلّ بالسابع؟
...السابع؟ اللعنة
.مات من العدوى
!سبعة أشخاص -
...رصاصة واحدة -
شراب للجميع -
!محاربٌ عظيم -
!(ارقص من أجلي (سود باستر
! ارقص كالدجاجة-
.!هذا صحيح ارقص -
ألديكَ ذرة في أذنيك يا صاح؟
!لم تدفع الرهن، لذا خسرتَ الأرض
.هذه القواعد الأساسيّة يا صديقي -
!لقد خرقتَ القانون -
إن رأيتُ وجهكَ في هذه البلدة مجدّداً، سأقطـّعه
.و أستخدمه لتنظيف ملابسي الداخليّة
.إهتمّ بأمر صاحب المنقار
!ولا تعد
علامَ تنظرون جميعاً؟
...بيل) الشرّير، ثمّة أمرٌ يجب)
ما هذا؟ -
(أتعرف من هذا (بيل)؟إنّه (رانغو -
.نعم! ليس خائفاً منك
.ليس خائفاً منكم
.(قتل الأخوة (جينكنز -
.(فعلها برصاصة واحدة (بيل -
!السبعة كلّهم -
أهذا صحيح؟ -
.دعني أمسح هذا عنك
!لا
!أعرف، هاك
...سأعتني بهذا من أجلك
!هاك
!هذا أفضل
...مهلاً، مهلاً
.إنتظر لحظة
حسناً، إسمعوا. أريدُ أن أعطيكم
.فرصةً أخيرة لإعادة التفكير
،و إن لم ترغبوا بإعادة التفكير
.فقد أفكّر بإعادة التفكير بنفسي
!و الآن هذا ما أتحدّث عنه
نعم. أصغوا الآن! ستتغيّر الأحوال هنا
.الآن بوجود (رانغو) في المدينة
،لديّ بعض القواعد الجديدة
،أريد أن يلمعَ حذائي عند كلّ صباح
.قهوتي ساخنة، و الدانماركيّون يقفون جانباً
!أيّما تفعلوه، فلا تنظروا في عينيّ
!إبقوا خارجَ نطاق رؤيتي
.(إنّه (رانغو -
!إلامَ يرمي؟ إنّه لا يخشى أحداً -
!سيُلقّن ذاك الطائر درساً
.عندما ترونني قادماً، تنحّوا جانباً
أنا أقومُ بخطواتٍ كبيرة و لا أريدُ
!مخلـّفاتكم على جزمتي
.و طبعاً، لا حاجةَ للعنف
.طالما نبقى معاً و نعمل كفريق
.لذا أريدكم أن تخرجوا الآن
!إصطفّوا في صفٍّ واحد، بينما أستريح قليلاً
ما الذي يفعله الآن؟ -
.أعتقدُ أنّه يتغوّط -
مشغول
!لا... لا تهتمّ
!يمكنكم أن تشاهدوا أفضل من هنا
ما الذي يفعله الآن؟ -
!إنّه يلاحق ذاك الصقر -
!(نَل منه (رانغو
!لا، لا
هل رأيتم ذلك؟ -
!لقد قتلَ ذلك الشيء -
ما... ما رأيكَ أيّها الطبيب؟ -
!هذا الصقر... ميّت -
..قـٌتِل
.أرى أن نطهوه فوراً
!فعلها برصاصةٍ واحدة -
!تماماً كما قال -
.حان الوقتُ لنحصل على بطلٍ هنا -
!بطل ليس في علبة صنوبر -
أعتقد أنّ الوقتَ حان ليقابل
.رئيس البلديّة
.أسمعتَ يا (رانغو)؟ ستقابل رئيس البلديّة -
!(هلّلوا لـ (رانغو -
و هكذا يتشمّس الغريبُ
.في تملـّق أصدقائه الجدد
.غارقاً أكثر في لذة إحتياله الخاص
متى سيموت؟ -
.قريباً يا صديقي. قريباً -
!أرضي ليست للبيع
!جئتُ لأنقذ أرضي، لا لأبيعها
أعتقدُ بإمكاننا التوصّلُ لشيءٍ
.معقولٍ إن تحدّثتِ معه فقط
بينز)، إلى أين تذهبين؟)
!(بينز)
.سيقابلكَ رئيس البلديّة الآن
.(ماءٌ يا سيّد (رانغو
.ماء
.من دونه لا شيءَ سوى ترابٌ و هباء
...لكن بوجود الماء
.توجدُ الحياة
انظر إليهم! يتوقون للحياة
.لدرجةِ أنّهم يتبعونه لأيّ مكان
.هذا هو القانونُ الثابتُ للصحراء
،إن سيطرتَ على الماء
.فبإمكانكَ السيطرةُ على كلّ شيءٍ
لكنّي لستُ مضطرّاً لقول ذلك لك
.بإعتباركَ رجلاً حقيقيّاً من الغرب
.نعم، الغرب هو الأفضل
.هذا من مخزوني الخاصّ
.ماءُ مطرٍ ممتازٍ من الطوفان العظيم
.(ليس طوفان (نوح
!ربّاه! لستُ معمّراً لتلك الدرجة
.أعتقدُ أنّ للسلطة إمتيازاتِها -
.وجهةُ نظرٍ سديدة يا بنيّ -
.لكنّ الإمتيازات ترافقها مسؤوليّات
!"اللعنة، كنتُ رئيس بلديّةٍ هنا قبل بناء "ديرت
...قد أكون مجرّدَ سلحفاةٍ عجوزٍ عاطفيّ
،لكن أعتقدُ أنّه ثمّةَ مستقبلٌ لهذه البلدة
.و أرجو أن تكون جزءاً منه
!"بصحّة "ديرت -
أتراهم يا سيّد (رانغو)؟
...جميعَ أصدقائي و جيراني
.الحياةُ قاسيةٌ هنا
.قاسيةٌ جدّاً
أتعرفُ كيف يصمدون يوماً بعد يوم؟
...يؤمنون
.يؤمنون أنّ الوضعَ سيتحسّن
!يؤمنون أنّ الماء سيأتي
يؤمنون رغمَ كلّ العقباتِ و الدلائل
.أنّ الغدَ سيكون أفضلَ من اليوم
.يجب أن يؤمن الناسُ بشيء
.و الآن... يؤمنون بك
.(خذها يا سيّد (رانغو
.قدركَ ينتظر
.يجب أن يؤمن الناسُ بشيء
.تكاد تحلّ الظهيرة
أكلّ شيءٍ جاهز؟
.نعم. لكنّه قد يكون مشكلة
.(ليس مشكلةً يا (ويليام
.و إنّما الحلّ
.الأمرُ غيرُ منطقيّ
،تبدو البلدةُ بأسرها تجفّ
!و وحده رئيس البلديّة لا يبدو متأثّراً
ألا يثيرُ ذلك شكوككَ قليلاً؟
و ماذا عن تلك المياه التي رأيتُها في الصحراء؟
!رأيتُها بأمّ عيني -
.لا بأس، لا بأس. ما من داعٍ لإثارة القلق -
.سأستفسرُ عن أمر رئيس البلديّة
،لكن إن كنتِ تشعرين فعلاً بوجود مؤامرة
!أقترحُ أن تُبلغيها للمأمور الجديد
.ستكون جيّدة
.انتبهي للإبرة هناك
،لا، لا تضيّقيها هكذا
.نريد مكاناً للإبزيم
.هذا جيّد
.رويدك هنا أيّها النمر
أعلى قليلاً و للخلف؟
.لا أظنّ ذلك -
هل سأحصل على أصفادٍ فرنسيّة معه؟ -
،(اعذرني يا حضرةَ المأمور (رانغو
...أرغب بالتحدّث معك
بينز)، ما رأيكِ بمظهري الجديد؟)
.خفّضتُ سعرَ قبّعة راعي البقر من 15 إلى 10
...هذا لطيف -
هل قابلتِ (آنجيليك)؟ -
.(مرحباً (بينز -
.(أهلاً (آنجيليك -
.سوقيّة -
.مقمّلة -
.ساقطة -
.(اعذرني سيّد (رانغو -
!سأطلقُ هذا على وجهكَ القبيح
...كنتُ أفكّر فقط أن -
تريد (جون هانكوك) القديم، أليس كذلك؟ -
.تفضّل، أمسك هذا -
!سيّد (رانغو)، هذه ليست زيارةً اجتماعيّة -
.فيه رصاصةٌ هناك -
.أعلم، أعلم بأمر الاجتماع ظهيرةَ اليوم -
.لقد طلبتُ بعض الملابس الفاخرة -
...أيّها المأمور، أريد التبليغ -
!(سيّد (رانغو -
...أنتِ أيضاً؟ لا مشكلة. دعيني فقط -
...أريدكَ أن تحقّق
أوَتعلمين يا (بينز)؟ أراهنُ أنّكِ
.ستبدين أفضل إن بذلتِ مجهوداً أكبر
!ماذا؟ -
.و الآن تذكّر يا بنيّ -
،ابقَ في مدرستك، تناول خضراواتك
.(و احرق كلّ شيءٍ ما عدا (شيكسبير
من يكون (شيكسبير)؟ -
أيّها المأمور(رانغو)إن كان هذا اسمكَ الحقيقيّ -
أحاولُ إنقاذ مزرعةِ والدي التي على وشك
!الإنهيار، بينما تقوم بمسرحيّة مع هذه الباغية
...مؤسفٌ فعلاً
.يا له من أمرٍ محزن
لماذا تفعل ذلك؟ -
.إنّه ردّة فعلٍ للنجاة -
.معيارها معطّلٌ و حسب -
.حسناً، هذا مزعج -
!ليست طفحاً
!إنّها ندبة ولادة
فعلتُها ثانيةً، أليس كذلك؟ -
فعلتِ ماذا؟ -
.دعني أطرح سؤالاً عليك
هل ذكر أحدٌ هنا ماذا حلّ بالمأمور السابق؟
...أيمكن أن أسأل... المعذرة... أيمكن أن أسأل
...المأمور... المأمور السابق. المعذرة
إلى أين يذهب الجميع؟
...ما الذي يحدث بالضبط لـ
* طوال اليوم *
* أواجه التبذير البالغ *
* دون تذوّق الماء *
* ماءٌ بارد *
* دان) العجوز و أنا) *
* جفّت حنجرتينا *
* و الأرواح تنوح *
* من أجل الماء *
* ماءٌ صافٍ * -
آسف. آسف -
.يا له من إجتماعٍ راقصٍ جميل
.ما زلتُ أتدرّب على الخطوات
أيُعتبر هذا سلوكاً مدنيّاً طبيعيّاً؟ -
.نعم. كلّ أربعاء. بكلّ إنتظام -
قتلتَ طائراً؟ -
.نعم. في الحقيقة قتلته -
.طائرٌ يموت. ثعبانٌ يأتي -
ثعبان؟ -
.(يقصد الثعبان المجلجل يا سيّد (رانغو
لم يحضر إلى البلدة قط
.لأنّه كان يخشى الصقر
.لكنّه قد يأتي الآن
أيمكنني الحصول على جزمتك عندما تموت؟
لا! لا يخشى (رانغو) الأفعى
.(المجلجلة (جيك
.هذا ما قاله (آموس) تماماً -
آموس)؟) -
(المأمور (آموس
الخميس - السبت
يرقد بسلام
ألديكَ أيّة حشوات ذهبيّة؟
!"رفاقي شعبَ "ديرت
!أرحّب بكم في يوم نجاتنا العظيم
!هللويا -
،أيّها المعاونون
!جهّزوا الحنفيّة المقدّسة
.لدينا وافدٌ جديدٌ بيننا اليوم يا أصدقائي
،رجلٌ يحتاج بعضَ التعريف لكم
.كان دخوله إلى مجتمعنا جريئاً للغاية
سيّد (رانغو)، هلاّ تقدّمت؟ -
أعطني إياه -
!لي! لي -
أعده لي -
.حان الوقت يا أصدقائي
.الوقتُ الذي تمّ التنبّؤ به -
!هللويا -
.الوقت المقدّس -
!لحظة المصير -
!هللويا -
!وقت النجاة -
!إنّه وقتُ الرطوبة
!لا
!هذا خطؤه -
!الوافد الجديد! احرقوه -
!إنه مشعوذ -
!سأحصلُ على جزمته -
!أصدقائي! أصدقائي
!اضبطوا إحباطكم
.ستصبحُ الأوقاتُ قاسيةً من الآن فصاعداً
.و يجب أن تُقدّم القرابين
،لكن إن استطعتُ المساعدة بأيّة طريقة
...أرجوكم اعلموا أنّ أبوابي دائماً -
!مهلاً مهلاً -
!هذا الأمر برمّته مشبوه
،أوّلاً يجفّ المصرف
!و الآن هذه الحنفيّة
جفّ المصرف؟ -
عمّ تتحدّث؟ -
!قالت ألاَّ ماءَ في المصرف
أعطنا الماء -
أعد إليّ مائي -
!هذا كلّ ما لدينا
!لا يمكننا توزيعه كلـّه
!كان ذلك حسابي المائيّ
لن يقع عصيانٌ مدني في بلدتي شكراً جزيلاً -
(اهلاً (رنغو -
.حمداً لله على وجودكَ أيّها المأمور
.بدأت الأمور تخرج عن السيطرة
.تفضّلوا، إنضمّوا إلينا -
.حسناً -
.دعوني أقدّر مقدار مصدر الحضارة هنا
.رحمة
حسناً أصغوا! كنتُ أفكّر
.و أعتقد أنّي توصّلتُ لشيء
!لديكم مشكلةُ مياه
،و الآن انتبهوا جميعاً
.فأنا أحاولُ إيضاح أمرٍ هنا
فلنفترض أنّ هذا الرفيقَ هنا
.يريد أن يأخذ شربةَ ماء
.شربة واحدة صغيرة فقط
لا ضرر، لا خطأ، صحيح؟
و أنت! بما أنّكَ جافٌّ كأرنبٍ
!أمريكيٍّ في تمّوز
!ستحتملُ إذاً أن يأخذ جرعةً مضاعفة
...ابقوا معي
،ماذا تعتقدون أنّه سيحدث حينها
إن شربنا جميعاً؟
!قبلَ أن تُدركوا، لن تكون هناك أيّة مياه
و أين سنكون حينئذ؟
!سنكون عطشانين
!عطشانين جدّاً
!و سننقلبُ على بعضنا كمجموعة حيوانات
.و الآن انظروا هنا
.لدينا ماءٌ يكفي ستّة أيّام
...لدينا ماءٌ يكفي خمسةَ أيـّا
.طالما لدينا ماء، فبلدتنا باقية
.المأمور (رانغو) على حقّ
.طالما لدينا هذا الماء، فلدينا بعض الأمل
.و بإمكانكم أن تصدّقوا كلامي
،وقتُ عملي الكامل من هذه اللحظة فصاعداً
.سيكون لحماية مصدرنا الطبيعيّ الغالي
!(و لن يتلاعبَ أحدٌ بـ (رانغو
.مساء الخير أيّتها السيّدتان -
.مساء الخير أيّها المأمور -
.رويدكَ (غوردي). عد للداخل و أفرض نفسك
.و أعتقد أنّك ستتفاجأ بمدى ضيافة شعب هذه البلدة
.شكراً أيّها المأمور -
!ماذا؟ انتَ مجدّداً -
.كنتُ مخطئاً
!هذا ليس المصرف -
!(قلت لكَ يا (جديدايا -
!قفا مكانكما -
.إنّه المأمور -
.إرفعا أياديكم إلى حيث أراها
.تماماً كما توقـّعت
!تنقيبٌ دون المعدّات المرخّصة
!لا تتحرّكا قيد أنملة -
تنقيب؟ -
،هاكما مجرفة، فأس، مثقابٌ معدنيّ
.وجبات سريعة، كتب ألغاز و تحتاجان لرخصة
إيزيكيال)! (جيديدايا)! ما الذي)
يحدث هناك بحقّ السماء؟
!كانت لديّ سعادين أذكى منكما
!اللعنة! هذا ليس المصرف -
أبي، المأمور يقف هنا -
.يقوم بمساعدتنا -
.سيعطينا رخصةً للتنقيب -
.هذا صحيح يا سيّدي
.أقوم بعملي فقط
الشرطيّ الوحيد الذي يقوم بدوريّاتٍ
.لمراقبة عمليّات الفوضى و التخريب
أيبدو شكله كمنطقه؟ -
.نعم -
حسناً أيّها المأمور، إن استخرجنا ثرواتٍ
،بصفتنا منقّبين و ما شابه
فأين سنضع إيداعاتنا السنويّة؟
،"حسناً، هنا في بلدة "ديرت
يصدفُ أنّه لدينا أفضل مؤسّسة
"ماليّة في هذا الجانب من "ميسوري
"مصرف  "ديرت
محميّةٌ صباحاً، ظهراً و ليلاً
.من قِبل مخلصكم
.تشرّفتُ كثيراً
!سُرقَ المصرف! سُرقَ المصرف
!يا إلهي، سُرقَ المصرف
ما الذي يحدث؟ -
!لا أدري. اختفى كلّ الماء -
ما الذي قاله؟ -
!قال أنّ المصرفَ قد سُرق -
،د.(ماركس)، أنا على نار
!عانقيني
* سُرقَ المصرف و جفّت البلدة *
* سنموتُ عطشاً *
* و الناس يبكون *
* وعدَ بحماية الخزنة *
* اختفى الماء و هذا ذنبه *
،حسناً يا رفاق، تراجعوا، أخلوا المنطقة
.باتت هذه ساحة جريمة الآن
،أمّنوا المحيط، ارفعوا البصمات، افحصوا الألياف
،ابحثوا عن عيّنات الحمض النوويّ
أريد عيّنةَ بولٍ من الجميع
.و أحضروا لي كوبَ لاتيه
.لا تخلطوا بين الاثنين -
ما هذا؟ -
رخصةُ تنقيب؟ -
!سآخذها. إنّها دليلٌ حسّي -
ماذا سنفعل الآن أيّها المأمور؟ -
.نحن بحاجة لتلك المياه -
!سنموت جميعاً -
.أصدقائي، كلّنا نعرفُ ما يتوجّبُ علينا فعله الآن -
.هذا صحيح
.كلـّنا نعرفُ ما يتوجّبُ علينا فعله الآن
و ما هو ذاك؟
."نشكّلُ مجموعة" -
.نشكّل حيوان أبوسوم -
.مجموعة
.سنقوم بهذا بالطريقة التقليديّة
أوّلاً، أيعرفُ أحدكم استخدام
سلاحٍ من أيّ نوع؟
.حسناً إذاً -
ماذا نفعل الآن أيّها المأمور؟ -
...الآن
.ننطلق
إلى أين نذهب؟ -
ماذا؟ -
إلى أين نذهب؟
بصفتكَ نائبي الآن، ستكون مسؤولاً
.عن ملاحقة و إيجاد الأشرار
.بإستعمال إبداعكَ الناشئ
.لا أقصد الإهانة
إلى أين ذهبوا برأيك؟
أتريدُ أن تشمّ الهواء أو تتواصل
مع البوفالو أو ما شابه؟
!أنتَ بارع
.(أعتمد عليكَ (سبونز
.يوجد بعض التبغ على لحيتك
من الأفضل دائماً أن نحظى
.برجل طبٍّ أيّها الطبيب
!يجب أن تتآزرَ الزواحفُ مع بعضها
أليس كذلك يا أخي؟
.أنا برمائيّ -
.لا يوجد عارٌ في هذا -
أواثقٌ أنّكَ ملائمٌ للمهمّة أيّها الجنديّ؟ -
ماذا؟ -
.حسناً، يوجد شيءُ في عينكَ هناك
.تلك! هذا رمدٌ يا سيّدي
.إنّه وراثيّ
.حسناً، يسرّني سماعُ أنّه غيرُ مُعدٍ
!و الآن انتظري دقيقةً مجنونةً ناعمة
...لا مكانَ في المجموعة لـ
.لا عليكِ
.مهلاً يا أختي الصغيرة
.يجب أن يهتمّ أحدٌ بالبلدة في غيابي
هل سيتسنّى لي إطلاقُ النار على أحد؟
.دعينا نؤجّل هذا الموضوع
،أيّها المأمور، ستعيد تلك المياه
أليس كذلك؟
.اعتمدي عليّ يا أختي الصغيرة
في أيّ طريقٍ نذهب أيّها المأمور؟ -
!ثمّةَ أنفاقٌ في كلّ مكان -
.البلدة بأكملها منخورةٌ بها -
.فيها فتحاتٌ أكثر من فراشة على قنفذ -
.لقد إصطحبني والدي إلى منزلها
.ليس هذا ما توقـّعتُه
كيف وجدوا المصرف على أيّ حال؟
...يا سادة، إن استطعنا الإلتزام بالمهمّة هنا -
.أيّها المأمور، إلى هنا -
!هلاّ نظرتم إلى ذلك؟ -
!كرؤيةِ عظمةِ الخالق -
.آمين يا أخي -
.أتذكّر حينما كان يتدفـّق كلّ أربعاء -
.كان ذلك عصرنا الذهبيّ -
.لا بدّ من سببٍ لتخلـّيها عنّا -
،أيّاً كان السبب
!فثمّةَ شيءٌ يتحكّم بالماء هنا
ما رأيكَ أيّها المأمور؟
من الواضح أنّ اللصوص جاءوا
.من هذا الإتّجاه
،أرى أن نتعقّب هذا الانبوب إلى أصله الهيدروليكيّ
.و نقبضَ على المسؤولين عن هذا اللغز المائيّ
ما الذي قاله؟ -
.أظنّه قال أن نتبعَ الأنبوب -
.قال أن نتبعَ الأنبوب -
.الأكيدُ وجودُ رطوبةٍ هنا -
.نعم، المكان أشبه بكومة طينٍ كبيرة -
.أزلتُ غدّتي الدرقيّة ذاتَ مرّة
.كانت تشبه(توني بينيت)لحظةَ خروجه من الحمّام
.وضعتُها على فطيرة
،مهما فعلتم
!فلا تنظروا للأسفل
ما هذا المكان؟ -
.إنّه خزّانٌ جوفيّ -
ما هو الخزّانٌ الجوفيّ؟ -
.أيّ للماء -
!حسناً، إنّه فارغٌ الآن
.هذا واحدةٌ كبيرة
.إنّها نهاية الطريق -
.لا تتقدّموا أكثر -
.ذاك هو الطريق
.لا بدّ أنّه متّصلٌ بشيء
.أنتَ كثير الكلام
لم لا تضع سدادةً فيه؟
...لم لا تضع أنتَ سدادةً في
.سأقول لك أين لا تُشعّ الشمس
.أمّكَ فعلتْها. سأطهوها فوراً -
لم تفهما بعد، أليس كذلك؟ -
.شخصٌ أو شيءٌ يعبثُ بمائنا
.و لذاك الأنبوب علاقةٌ بذلك
!ظننتُ أنّنا نلاحق لصوص المصرف -
.نحن نواجه تغييراً في المهام -
!سأغيّرُ خريطةَ وجهك ما لم تخرس -
!تعال و حاول -
.صمتاً أيّها الهمج! كفّوا عن العراك
.إنّكم تشتّتون تأمّلي
!عجباً، لقد وجدتُها
!أطفئوا مشاعلكم
.بكلّ تأكيد -
!تفكيرٌ ذكيٌّ يا صاح -
!ابدءوا بالتسلـّق -
!أبعد جزمتكَ عن وجهي -
ليس سيّئاً، أليس كذلك (بينز)؟ -
.إن واصلتَ التفكير هكذا، ستشتعل قبّعتك -
...كما تعلمين
...نسير على الطريق
.ساخن، ساخن. يحرق
،يا لها من مسكينة
.جلّ ما أرادتْه هو القليل من الماء
صبّارٌ يموتُ من العطش؟
.هذا لا يُبشّرُ بخير
.انظروا ماذا وجدت -
ماذا لديك هناك؟ -
!رأيتُها أوّلاً -
!فيها بعض الماء -
!إنّها لي -
!هاتِها -
.إنّها فارغة بأيّ حال -
.كنتُ أعلم... كنتُ أعلم ذلك -
أين وجدتَها؟ -
!أيّها المأمور، يجب أن ترى هذا -
.إنّه السيّد (ميرماك) من المصرف -
ما الذي يفعله هنا؟ -
.فليتراجع الجميع -
.حسناً، دعوني أرَ -
.يبدو أنّ اللصوص أطلقوا النار عليه من الخلف -
.لا، هذا الرجل لم يتعرّض لإطلاق نار -
!و إنّما غرق
غرق؟ -
في وسط الصحراء؟ -
.يا لها من طريقة للموت
...حسناً إذاً
لمن آثار هذه الجزمة؟
.هذا مثيرٌ للاهتمام. ما زالت الأرضُ رطبة -
.أظنّ علينا أن ندفنه -
.لا أعلم، يجب أن تأكل الطيور أيضاً -
!إنّها دورة الحياة -
.أيّها المأمور
هلاّ قلتَ بضعةَ كلمات؟
.نعم. نعم
.أحبّائي
اجتمعنا اليومَ هنا
.لتكريم هذا الرجل
...(أيّها السيّد (ميرماك
.لكَ الحقّ أن تبقى صامتاً
.تكلّم الآن أو أرقد بسلامٍ إلى الأبد
آمين -
ما الذي يفعله ذاك الهنديُّ الأحمق؟
.أرى أنّكَ تتشاور مع الأرواح -
.لا، بل أتجدّد. أيّ أتحضّر للتزاوج -
.سأُبقي هذا في بالي
.فاكهة الصبّار -
.نعم. فاكهة الصبّار القديمة -
أعتقدُ أنّكم تستخدمونها كمقبّلات
.بينما تحضّرون وجباتكم المحلّيّة
.كما أنّها مسهّلاتٌ طبيعيّة
.وجدتُ أثراً. ثلاثة رجال اتّجهوا غرباً
...أحدهم أعمى، و أحدهم لديه
.بروستات ضخم
.و لديهم سرجٌ جانبيّ
ماذا؟ ماذا قال؟ -
.لديهم سرجٌ جانبيّ -
ماذا؟ -
.إنّنا نهمس -
ماذا قال؟ -
.أحدهم لديه مجارٍ سيّئة -
حسناً، من يشعرُ منكم أنّه بحاجة لفحص؟
.غريب
ما الذي سنفعله الآن بالتحديد؟
...الآن
!ننطلق
!يعني أن ننطلق الآن
.في هذه اللحظة
تذكّرني حلوى الخطمي بالتخييم
.مع والدي. كنتُ أستطيع تناولها طوال الليل
طبعاً كان يجعلني أتجشّأها
.ثانيةً من أجل الإفطار
،في إحدى المرّات
.تجشّأتُ جرواً كاملاً
.هذا لا يُذكر
.تجشّأتُ قبيلةً كاملةً من الأقزام
.بدءوا ينظرون إليّ بطريقةٍ غريبة -
.تذكّرتُهم. كانوا ودودين للغاية -
وجدتُ عموداً فقريّاً بشريّاً
.في برازي ذات مرّة
.لربّما يجب أن تعيدَ النظرَ إليه
.(مرّري لي الفاصولياء يا (بينز
أيّها المأمور؟ -
.لا، شكراً -
سيّد (رانغو)، أيمكنكَ أن تروي لنا
عن روح الغرب؟
.نعم، تحدّث عن ذلك -
أصحيحٌ ما يقولونه؟ -
.نعم، روح الغرب
.المثاليّ مستحيل الإدراك
يقولون أنّه يركبُ عربةً من مرمر
.مع حرّاسٍ ذهبيّين ليحموه
لكنّه يظهر فقط لمن
.خاض رحلةً ملحميّة
.و نجح في الوصول إلى الجانب الآخر
الجانبُ الآخر لماذا؟ -
.إنّه تعبيرٌ مجازيّ -
!آه، عيني -
.ستُشفى سريعاً -
أيّها المأمور، ما الذي ستفعله
حيال الثعبان (جيك)؟
ماذا؟ أين؟
.آسفٌ على ذلك
.القصدُ أنّكَ ستواجهه مرّةً أو مرّتين
.(نعم. (جيك
.تقصد أخي
أخوك؟ -
!هذا ما قلتُه -
.لكنّه ثعبان و أنتَ سحليّة
حسناً، كانت لوالدتي حياةٌ
.إجتماعيّةٌ حافلة
أسبقَ و لدغكَ قطّ؟ -
.بالتأكيد. انظر لهذا الصغير -
.هيّا، بإمكانكَ أن تلمسه -
.هذا مثير. إنّها سرّة -
.لحسن الحظّ أنّي منيعٌ ضدّ سمّه
.أنا أضيف القليل منه لقهوتي لأحصل على نكهة
أصحيحٌ أنّه لا يخشى سوى الصقور؟ -
.هذا ما ندعوه العدوّ الطبيعيّ -
كلّ هذا الكلام عن مطاردات الأشرار
.جعل ريشاتي تقشعّر
.لن أنام ليلاً. لا يا سيّدي -
.لا تقلقوا من شيء -
بحلول الغد سنجد تلك المياه
!و نعود ليستقبلونا استقبال الأبطال
،يا أصدقاء، قبل أن نخلدَ للنوم
.أودّ أن نشبكَ أيدينا للحظة
.و نقول بضعةَ كلماتٍ لروح الغرب
.فكرةٌ جيّدة
لم نتحدّث إليك بشكلٍ صائبٍ
،دائماً يا روح الغرب
لكنّي أرغبُ الليلةَ أن أشكركَ لإحضار
.المأمور (رانغو) إلى حياتنا
.حياتنا قاسية
،و أحياناً لا أعرفُ كيف سنمضيها
لكن بطريقةٍ ما، جعلني المأمور
.رانغو) أعتقد أنّنا سننجح)
.احتجنا شجاعاً فأرسلتَه لنا
.من اللطيف أن يكون لدينا من نثق به
.شكراً يا روح الغرب
.آمين
.كنتُ أتحقّق و حسب
.الطقس باردٌ الليلة -
.شكراً لك -
أسبقَ و أحسستِ أنّ هذه
الأشياء تنظر إليكِ؟
هذا الخنجر الإسبانيّ. لكنّنا ندعوه هنا
.الصبّار السائر
سائر؟ -
.ثمّةَ إسطورةٌ أنّه جال الصحراء بحثاً عن الماء -
حينما كنتُ صغيرةً، كنتُ أسهر
.و أراقبه إن كان سيتحرّك
ظننتُ أنّي لو تبعتهم، لقادوني
.إلى مكانٍ رائع
.إلى مكانٍ فيه ما يكفي من الماء للجميع
.ليلةً بعد أخرى راقبتهم
.لم أرَهم يتحرّكون قطّ
لكنّكِ ما تزالين تراقبين؟ -
من لا يرغب بإيجاد مكانٍ رائع؟ -
.(سنجدُ الماء يا (بينز
.أعدكِ بذلك
.يا له من صوتٍ وحيد
أسبقَ و شعرتَ بالوحدة؟ -
.أحياناً -
.يصعبُ تصديقُ ذلك
.فأنتَ جذابٌ و يحبّك الجميع كثيراً
.لم أكوّن صداقات قط بتلك السهولة -
حقّاً؟ -
.لا، فنحن معزولون جدّاً في مزرعتنا
.و كأنّنا محتجزون في صندوقٍ صغير
.لا نرى الكثير من الناس
.ما كنتُ لأعرفَ ذاك الشعور
أهناكَ شخصٌ مميّزٌ
في حياتك (رانغو)؟
.فيما مضى. لكنّها لم تستطع الحفاظَ على رأسها
.كما أنّ حياتي خطيرةٌ على أمورٍ كهذه
أوَتعرفين، لمن المريع التواجد
.وحيداً هناك على المرج
...إجتياز المسافات و ما شابه
بينز)؟)
!سأسلخكَ حيّاً أيّها الفتى -
لا ، لا -
!سأجلدكَ كولدٍ متبنّىَ أحمر الرأس
لئيمون غاضبون، أليس كذلك؟ -
.عائلة متفكّكة. تحتاج لتدخّل -
ما ذاك القادم؟
.إنّها المياه
! مياه -
تلك هيَ -
.لديّ خطّة
.و لكلٍّ منكم دورٌ يؤدّيه
ماذا سأفعل أنا؟ -
!سبونز)، لديكَ الدور الأهمّ على الإطلاق) -
،ستبقى على الحافّة، و إن حدث خطب
.ستعطينا... الإشارة
بينز)، أيّ قياسٍ ترتدين؟)
!لقد نجحت -
!هللويا -
.جلبتُ الماء -
.نجحت يا بنيّ -
...حسناً في الحقيقة -
لمَ لا تكون كأخيك؟ -
أبي، بخصوص الماء، ثمّة أمرٌ
.يجب أن أقوله لك
!اصمت الآن. أحدهم قادم
مرحباً سيّدي. مساء الخير
!لكَ و لكَ و لك
أتسمحون أن أقدّم لكم فرقة الممثّلين
.(الجوّالين للسيّدة (لوبون
ما ذاك؟ -
!أظنّهم ممثّلين -
ممثّلون؟ هذا غير قانونيّ
!في سبع ولايات
.المسرح جاهز
.الأميرة تتحضّر لتنتحر
.أتوق للحبّ
في هذه الأثناء، الحارس الوحيد
.يراقب عند بوّابة القلعة
...يراقب عند بوّابة القلعة
هارك)، من يذهب إلى هناك؟)
.هذه الحبكة متوقـّعة جدّاً -
!صمتاً! هذا جزئي المفضّل -
يصل إلى الاستعراض الموسيقيّ
.والدها العجوز
.(تكلّم (كيوبيد
.ابنتي الجميلة اللطيفة
...و يصل إلى
الخط؟ -
!اذهب إلى السماء -
ما ذاك؟ -
.لا بدّ أنّه مسرحٌ واقعيّ -
أنتم محاصرون! أنتَ و كامل عائلتك
.ارفعوا أياديكم حيث أراها
عائلتي بأكملها؟
* حصى و بصاق و خسّ أخضر *
* وافل أمعاء، و أدمغة قردة *
* عظامٌ مقليّة و دمّ متخثّر *
* بيضٌ مخلـّل و أطباق طين *
.إنّه بيتٌ عامر
يبدو أنّنا سنحظى بمواجهةٍ
.تقليديّة قديمة
يجب أن أُعلمكَ أنّكَ لا تنظر
.إلى كلّ فريقنا
ما ذاك؟
ماذا يُفترضُ بذلك أن يكون؟
.تلك الإشارة -
.تلك الإشارة. لا بدّ أنّه وقعَ خطبٌ ما -
إذاً... أيُفترضُ حدوث شيء؟
.أنا أتقبّل الإقتراحات
!إهربوا
!إصعد إلى العربة
أيُفترض أن نقوم ببعض الرياضة
يا أطفال؟
.يعجبني حينما يهربون -
!مايبل)، أطلقي الصرخة) -
!يبدو أنّنا نجونا -
.ذاك الجمهور كان متجاوباً جدّاً -
نعم، أظنّ أنّ تلك الصفة
.على وشك التلاشي
!هناك خفافيش
.أمسكي! قودي أنتِ
.!يبدو أنّنا سنتناول الحساء الليلة
.هيّا اقضوا عليهم
!ما خطبك؟ لا تُطلق على الماء
"جديدايا)، حان وقت صندوق عصر "آلاباما)-
!حسناً يا أبي -
.أشعر بعدوانيّة -
!إنّهم قادمون -
!مرحباً
!وداعاً
!أمسك ذاك الخنزير
!أقترح أن نقوم بمراوغة -
!أقترح أن تخرس و تطلق النار -
ماذا حدث للمأمور؟ -
!يخوض إشتباكاً -
!بوسيفاس)، أعطِهم بعض الطلقات)
ما كان ذلك؟
!إذهب و تحقّق
ما الأمر؟ أهناك مشكلة؟
.بإمكانكِ أن تدعيها كذلك
.مشكلة
أهذا كلّ ما لديك؟
!لم يكن ذلك مزعجاً بالكامل
.خذ، أمسك هذه
!أبعد يديكَ عنّي
.آسفة
!إقفزي
.مستحيل
.لا يمكن. إنّها فارغة
!لا توجد مياه -
لا مياه؟ فعلامَ كنّا نتعارك بحقّ الجحيم؟ -
سيّدي، لقد شوّهتَ و دنّستَ
!مصدر عيشنا
.أظنّ أنّ صاحب الفستان هو المأمور -
أهو نفسه من أعطانا رخصةَ التنقيب؟ -
ماذا؟ -
!ليس للأمر علاقة! هذا تشويش -
أنتَ و قريبك رهن الإعتقال لسرقة المصرف
،و قتل مستشارنا الماليّ المحبوب
،(يوهانس ميرماك الثالث)
.(المعروف بـ (فلافي جو = ذو الزغب
.أيّها المأمور، لم نقتل أحداً
.حفرنا نحو الخزنة لكن لم يكن فيها شيء
.سرق أحدهم المصرف قبل أن نسرقه -
فمن أين أتيتم بتلك القارورة؟ -
.هذا ما كنتُ أحاول قوله يا أبي
.وجدتُها في الصحراء
فلماذا أحضرتَها بحقّ الجحيم؟ -
!مهلاً -
تقول أنّ القارورة كانت فارغةً
عندما وجدتَها؟
.هذا صحيح -
.لا أصدّق كلمةً من ذلك -
!فلنشنقهم أيّها المأمور -
!فلنعلـّقهم -
من عساه يهدر المياه في الصحراء؟ -
.لن تكون المرّةَ الأولى -
!إنّه لغز! كأنّه لعبة كلمات كبيرة -
ماذا يحدث أيّها المأمور؟ -
لا أعلم. لكنّي سأُعرّي هذا اللغز
.و أُظهر أجزاءه الخاصّة
.أنتَ و قريبكَ ستأتيان معي
!إنّهم قادمون
!ها هم آتون
.يبدو أنّهم قبضوا على اللصوص
أين المياه؟
.لم تكن هناك أيّة مياه
إلى أين يذهب؟
.إنّه ذاهبٌ لرؤية رئيس البلديّة
سيكون مسروراً بذلك -
رمية جيّدة يا زعيم -
.هذا مثيرٌ للإهتمام
،(أعتذر بخصوص الحذاء يا سيّد (رانغو
.لكن ثمّة قواعد لهذه اللعبة كم تعلم
.و أنا متمسّكٌ بالقواعد -
...حسناً، هذا جيّد -
لأنّه توجد بضعة أسئلة لتجيبَ عليها
.و أنا لديّ قواعدي الخاصّة
و لماذا قد يقوم أيّ شخصٍ
بسكب الماء في الصحراء؟
يبدو ساذجاً قليلاً أن نصدّق
.لصوص المصرف
.كما أنّهم عندما يُشنقون، سينتهي عملك
!أحسنت -
!أُنجز العمل جيّداً -
.لكنّ أحدهم سرق المصرف قبل وصولهم -
و من هو ذاك يا سيّد (رانغو)؟ -
.كنتُ أرجو أن تخبرني -
.يبدو ذلك ملامساً لحدود الإتّهام -
.إعتبره كما تشاء
.قلتَ أمراً لا ينفكّ يطنّ في أذني -
ما هو؟ -
،إن سيطرتَ على الماء"
".فبإمكانكَ السيطرةُ على كلّ شيءٍ
.(كفاكَ يا سيّد (رانغو
.إنّكَ تنسب لي قدرةً قدسيّة
كيف عساي أسيطر على الماء
بحقّ الأرض؟
.واضحٌ أنّكَ أتقنتَ هذه اللعبة
.حسناً، أمارسها منذ وقتٍ طويلٍ يا سيّدي
كنتُ هنا قبل أن يقسم
.الطريقُ السريعُ الواديَ
،راقبتُ مسيرةَ التقدّم
.و تعلّمتُ أمراً أو أمرين
،ربّما حان الوقتُ لتأخذ نظرةً أوسع
.و تبدأ بتقدير دورة التاريخ
.انظر هناك يا بنيّ
.يمكنكَ أن ترى الوقتَ يمضي
ما الذي تبنيه هنا؟ -
.المستقبل يا سيّد (رانغو)، المستقبل
،كلّ هذا سيتحوّل تدريجيّاً لأسطورة
.البلدة الحدوديّة، رجل القانون، حامل السلاح
.لم يعد لهم مكانٌ بعد الآن
.بتنا متحضّرين الآن
.صحيح، متحضّرون -
.هذا ما يحمله لنا المستقبل -
،إمّا تكون جزءاً منه
.أو يتخطّاك
أهذا ما حلّ بالسيّد (ميرماك)؟
هل تمّ تخطّيه؟
.(حذارِ يا سيّد (رانغو
.يبدو أنّكَ نسيتَ أنّكَ مجرّد سحليّةٍ واحدة
،يبدو أنّكَ أنتَ من نسي
.أنا ممثّل القانون في هذه الأرجاء
،لعبَ مأمورنا الجديد دورَ البطل طويلاً
.لدرجة أنّه بات يصدّق ذلك
.(إستدعي الثعبان (جيك
.لكنّ (جيك) يعني الموت
.فهو لا يرحل أبداً دون إزهاق روح
!نفّذ
لا تتحرّك. يجب أن يكون مظهركَ
.مقبولاً لتقابل خالقك
* ها قد وصل الموت *
* كيف سينجو البطل؟ *
إشترى رئيسُ البلديّة الأرضَ في الوادي
.(بإستثناء مزرعتكِ يا آنسة (بينز
.هذا غير منطقيّ
.فمن دون ماء، تلك الأرض بلا فائدة
.إلاّ إن كان يتحكّم بالماء
!كمثانة قرد
بعدها يستطيع إعادة المياه
.عندما يشتري كلّ الأرض
لكن كيف يتحكّم بالماء؟
.حسناً، يجب تمضية بعض الوقت لتدريبهم
،فكما تعرفين، عندما تتبوّل القردة
.نفركُ أنوفهم
.أيّها المأمور، لدينا مشكلة
.(تمهّلي (بينز
.لن يكون ذلك ضروريّاً
!اشنقوه حتّى يتحوّل إلى أزرق -
!سلّمونا اللصوص -
!مهلاً! اهدءوا جميعاً
!دعوني أتحدّث
!علّقوهم على حائط المحكمة -
.اهدءوا جميعاً -
أخرجهم من هناك حتّى
!ننتزعَ أحشاءهم
أنتَ أيضاً (سبونز)؟
.سلبونا تلك المياه
!لذا فقد سلبونا كلّ ما نملك
.لن يعلّق أحدٌ أحداً
.طالما و أنا مأمور
!لكن كلّ هذا ذنبه -
.قلتَ أنّك ستعيد الماء -
.لن يكون لنا أملٌ دون تلك المياه -
.لم يبقَ لدينا ما نؤمن به -
أترون تلك اللافتة هناك؟
،"طالما عليها كلمة "مأمور
فيمكنكم أن تؤمنوا بوجود
.القانون و النظام في هذه البلدة
،لكن دون القانون و النظام
.تأمّلوا ذلك. نعم
.سيبدأ الأمر ببطئٍ كالفطر
.أحدهم يشتم. تتطاير الإتّهامات
،ينقلب الجارُ على جاره
!و سرعان ما نأكل أولادنا
ثمّ تجتمع الكلاب و الهررة معاً ليكوّنوا
!كلّ أنواع التشوّهات غير الطبيعيّة
لذا أتريد شيئاً لتثقَ به (سبونز)؟
.ثق بي
.ثقوا بتلك اللافتة
،فطالما تبقى معلّقةً هناك
.سيكون لدينا أمل
.مرحباً أخي
أأنتَ عطشان؟
.مرّ وقتٌ طويلٌ يا أخي
كيف كانت أحوالك؟
...حسناً، كما تعرف
.(سمعتُ أنّكَ رويتَ عن قتلكَ للأخوة (جينكنز
برصاصةٍ واحدة، أليس كذلك؟
أليس ذلك صحيحاً؟
جميعُ هؤلاء الرفاق الطيّبون يصدّقون
قصصكَ القصيرة، أليس كذلك؟
لأنّهم يعتقدون أنّكَ قاتلٌ
صلبٌ، أليس كذلك؟
.يبدو أنّ هؤلاء الرفاق يثقون بك
.يعتقدون أنّكَ ستنقذ هذه البلدة الصغيرة
!يعتقدون أنّكَ ستنقذ أرواحهم
لكنّنا نعرف الحقّ، أليس كذلك؟
فلمَ لا تُري أصدقاءكَ حقيقتك؟
.أرِهم من أنتَ فعلاً
لمَ لا تُشهر مسدّسكَ و تُطلق عليّ؟
.لكنّك لن تحتاجها كلـّها بالتأكيد
رصاصة واحدة، صحيح؟
.هيّا أيّها البطل. إضغط على الزناد
أهناك قاتلٌ في داخلكَ يا بنيّ؟
.لستُ أراه
لم تفعل أيّاً ممّا قلتَه، أليس كذلك؟
.(لم تقتل الأخوة (جينكنز
لستَ من الغربِ حتّى! أليس كذلك؟
!قلها
.صحيح -
.إرفع صوتك. لا أظنّ أصدقاءكَ قد سمعوك -
.كلّ ما فعلتَه هو الكذبُ على هؤلاء الطيّبين -
.ما أنتَ إلاّ مزيّفٌ و جبان
أليس هذا صحيحاً؟
.نعم -
!أعلى -
.نعم
.اسمع أيّها المحتال المثير للشفقة
.هذه بلدتي الآن
،إن رأيتُكَ مجدّداً
!فسأرسل روحكَ مباشرةً إلى الجحيم
من أنت؟
من أنا؟
.أنا نكرة
.الحرّاس الذهبيّون
.عربة المرمر
.روح الغرب
المعذرة؟
أيّها الروح، سيّدي؟
هناك جَمال. علينا أحياناً أن نحفرَ
.عميقاً لنجدَ ما نبحث عنه
.نجحتَ إذاً
أهذه الجنّة؟ -
.(لو كانت الجنّة، لكنّا نأكل الفطائر مع (كيم نوفاك -
.نعم
.بالتأكيد
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟ -
.أبحث، مثلك -
.لم أعد أعرف عمّا أبحث حتّى
.لا أعرف من أكون
.إعتادوا مناداتكَ بالرجل بلا اسم
في هذه الأيّام، لديهم أسماء
.لكلّ شيءٍ تقريباً
.لا يهمّ بما ينادونك
.إنّما الأفعال هي التي تصنع الإنسان
.نعم، لكنّ أفعالي زادت الأمور سوءاً
!أنا محتال. مزيّف
،وثقَ أصدقائي بي
.لكنّهم يحتاجون بطلاً من نوعٍ ما
.فكن بطلاً إذاً -
.لا، لا. لم تفهم. لم يُفترض أن أكون هنا حتّى -
صحيح. قطعتَ مسافةً طويلة
.لتجدَ شيئاً غير موجودٍ هنا
ألا ترى؟
.الأمرُ ليس عنك
.و إنّما عنهم
.لكنّي لا أستطيع العودة -
.لا أعرف إن كان لديك خيارٌ يا بنيّ -
.لا يمكن لإنسانٍ أن يستقيل من تاريخه
.نجحتَ إذاً
.هذا صحيح يا صديقي
.إنّه الطرف الآخر من الطريق
أرأيتَ هذا للتو؟
.كلٌّ منّا يرى ما يجب أن يراه
جميل، أليس كذلك؟
.نعم
.جميل
.تعال يا صديقي
.أريد أن أريك شيئاً
منذ سنواتٍ طويلة، كان هذا الوادي
.بأكمله مغموراً بالماء
.و الآن، سؤالٌ واحدٌ يبقى
إلى أين ذهب؟
.يتبعون الماء
!إنّهم يتبعون الماء! هيّا بنا
.هذا غير منطقيّ
.فمن دون الماء، تلك الأرض عديمة الفائدة
ما الذي تبنيه هنا؟ -
.(المستقبل يا سيّد (رانغو -
،إمّا تكون جزءاً منه
.أو يتخطـّاك
كنتُ هنا قبل أن يفصل
.الطريقُ السريعُ الوادي
،راقبتُ موكبَ التقدّم
.و تعلـّمتُ أمراً أو أمرين
،تحكّم بالماء"
".فتتحكّم بكلّ شيء
.(كفاكَ يا سيّد (رانغو
.إنّكَ تنسبُ لي قوّةً مقدّسة
كيف بحقّ الأرض
أستطيع التحكّم بالماء؟
إغلاق طارئ
الصمّام 6
ماذا الآن يا صديقي؟
.لا يمكن لإنسانٍ أن يستقيل من تاريخه
.سأعود
لكن لماذا؟
.لأنّ تلك حقيقتي
.جرأتكَ كبيرةٌ للحضور إلى هنا يا رجل القانون
ما الذي تريده؟
الوالد و الولدان على وشكِ أن يُشنقوا
.عقاباتً على عملٍ لم يرتكبوه
.لكن لديّ خطـّة
.(أقدّر صعوبةَ الأمر عليكِ (بينز
.لكنّكِ تتّخذين قراراً عمليّاً
.قراراتٌ و قرارات -
.لا حاجةَ للمزيد من المعاناة -
مزرعة عائلتكِ ليست إلاّ
.أرضٌ مقفرةٌ الآن
،وقـّعي الإتّفاق
.و أريحي نفسكِ من عبءِ أبيكِ
!لم يكن والدي عبئاً
!إحتفظ بمالكَ و سأحتفظ بأرضي
،إفعلي ما يقول، و إلاّ بحقّ نيران الحفرة السوداء
!سأقتلعُ عينيكِ البنيّتين الجميلتين من جمجمتك
...تمهّل (جيك). لا حاجةَ لـ -
!دعني أُنجز عملي -
أنتَ إستدعيتَني و الآن سنستمرّ
!بالأمر حتّى النهاية
!وقـّعي الورقةَ اللعينة يا امرأة -
!إذهب للجحيم -
و من أين تخاليني أتيت؟
.انظري في عينيّ. أريد أن أراكِ تموتين
!(جيك)
!أستدعيكَ للخارج
!(جيك) -
.أصبح هذا اليوم أكثر تشويقاً -
.أنزلها -
و إلاّ ماذا أيّها الصغير؟ ستقتلني؟ -
.هذا وصفٌ قريبٌ لذلك
!أبعدا أياديكما عنّي -
!أغلقي فمكِ -
،حسناً أيّها المأمور
.قم بحركتك
!الآن يا رفاق
!اسحبوا! اسحبوا
.كانت فكرةً سيّئة
أأنتَ عطشانٌ يا أخي؟
!ها هي قادمة
!لا. لا
!إنّها معجزة -
!إنتبهوا -
!انظر هناك -
ما هذا؟ -
!إنّه مهربنا يا أبي -
!هذا هروبٌ من السجن يا ولديّ! سنهرب -
سأضع ثقوباً عديدةً بكَ
!حتّى يتسرّب الرصاص من أحشائك
حسناً، من الجيّد إذاً أنّي
.أحضرتُ بعض المساندة
ماذا؟
.لا يوجد صقر
!ليست سوى خفافيش
!فلنلتزم بالخطـّة يا أولاد
!دعونا نستنفذ ذخيرته
.الأمر يتطلـّب رصاصةً واحدة فقط -
.لا تملك الشجاعة -
.جرّبني
.(سيّد (رانغو
ألم تنسَ أمراً؟
.ناولني مسدّسكَ أيّها المأمور
.(الآن يا سيّد (رانغو
.بينز)! تماسكي)
.لا تقلقي، لديّ خطـّة
!النجدة
!افتحوا الباب
.حسناً، الخطـّة البديلة
ماذا؟
.بينز)، أنتِ تتمتمين)
.حُلـّت كلُّ مشاكلي
.بإستثناء واحدة
.(إنّه الغرب الجديد (جيك
.و لم يعد هناك مكانٌ لحملةِ الأسلحة
.بتنا رجالَ أعمالٍ الآن -
.نعم، حصلنا على قبّعاتٍ جديدة -
،من حيث أتيت
.ندعوا هذا إرتجالاً
.لقد عدت
ما كان ذلك؟ -
.لا داعٍ للفزع. لكن أظنّكِ إبتلعتِ الخطـّة البديلة-
ماذا؟
.حسناً، وقتُ الهلع
.أنتَ و المأمور أكثر شبهاً ممّا تظنّ
.لستما سوى إسطورتين
و قريباً لن يُصدّق أحدٌ
.أنّكما كنتما موجودَين حتّى
.رصاصةٌ أخيرة لقتل آخر خارجٍ عن القانون
.يا له من توافق
،أيّها المأمور، يمكننا العمل معاً
يمكننا التوصّل لفوائد مشتركة
.لموقعنا الحاليّ
.من الأفضل أن تتفاوض معه
.رصاصة واحدة
،أرفع قبّعتي لك
.من إسطورةٍ لآخر
ما ذاك الذي قلتَه؟
قريباً لن يُصدّق أحدٌ"
".أنّكما كنتما موجودَين حتّى
!لا (جيك)! لا
!(رانغو)
،أعدتَ الماء
.تماماً كما وعدت
.أنتَ بطلٌ فعلاً
...حسناً، بخصوص الأبطال، أنّهم عندما -
.لا تُفسد الأمر -
.صحيح
،لا أعرف بخصوصكم
.لكنّي ذاهبٌ للغطس
.و هكذا أكمل السحليّة رحلتَه
.من التواضع إلى الإسطورة التي نغنّيها اليوم
،و بالرغم من أنّ موتَه محتوم
،ربّما جرّاءَ حادثٍ منزليّ
،و الذي يُعدّ 65% من الوفيّات غير الطبيعيّة
لكنّ سكّان القرية سيُشرّفون ذكراه
.حتّى لو تخلـّوا عن كرامتهم
"مرحباً بكم في "مود
مود = طين
(مرحبا (بادبيل
.. أنا ذاهبة إلى -
.ماذا عن ماءٍ بارد؟ -
.الماء ليس مالاً. النقود هي المال
.حسناً، لا أملك أيّ مال -
نحن نتحدث بالعملة الصعبة -
.لدينا مشكلة -
من ترك (سنغلز) في الحوض مجدّداً؟ -
.أعتقد فعلاً أنّكِ تكمّلينني
.من فضلك، حرّر فتاتي
.اقطع التصوير. فليأخذ الجميع 5 دقائق -
كيف يستطيعون أخذها مرّةً أخرى؟ -
ما هو حافزي ؟
.يا لكم من أشقياء
.لمَ فعلتِ ذلك
.كنتُ أتحقّق و حسب
،سمعتُ أنّه لو حرقتكَ الشمس كثيراً
.فبإمكانك أن تقشّر وجهك
ما هذا؟ -
.إنّه طحالٌ بشريّ -
.لا تلمسوه -
.هذه المرّة الثانية التي يحدث لي ذلك -
.هذه المياه رائعة -
.أنا أتبوّل الآن -
.سباحة الراشدين بعد خمسة دقائق
.إبقوا بين الطوّافات
جهّزتُ غداءك. الطعام الدانماركيّ فيه
.و انتقيتُ الزبيب كما تحبّه
...لا تنسَ رذاذ الأنف في السرج -
!(بينز) -
...و كريم الترطيب -
.بينز)، لقد تحدّثنا بهذا الأمر) -
كريم ترطيب؟ -
.لمسدّسي.إنّه مرطـّب المسدّس -
أيّها المأمور، إلى أين تتّجه؟
.ثمّة مشكلة في الجدول الجافّ
.أساءَ (بيل) الشرّير التصرّفَ مجدّداً
.عزيزي، عد بكامل سلامتك
.و لا تحاول التصرّف كبطل
.بينز)، يفوتك المغزى)
.لديّ صورةٌ يجب أن أحافظ عليها الآن
أين علكتي الـ "تيك تاك"؟
.و جدتها -
ما الذي يحدث؟ -
،حسناً، لإرضاء حاجة الجماعة
،على البطل أن يهجرَ نفسه
و يُجنّد صورته كأيقونةٍ
.خالدةٍ في الذاكرة
.فإذاً، هذا مشهد الغروب
.إمنحهم عرضاً جيّداً يا صديقي
مستعدٌّ يا (إكسيلسيور)؟
.رفاقي
.قد يحلّ وقتٌ نشكّكُ فيه بأنفسنا
،عندما تشعرون بضربةٍ من مصائب الحياة
.تذكّروا هذه اللحظة. تذكّروني
،إعلموا أنّي سأكون أراقبكم
.و أحياناً في لحظاتٍ غير لائقة
.هذا جزءٌ من الإتّفاق
،و تذكّروا، بينما نستقرّ جميعاً
...فإنّ الروح الحقيقيّة للغـ
.دعونا نُعِدها من البداية
© ترجمة : علي رمضان